<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
or more contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file
distributed with this work for additional information
regarding copyright ownership.  The ASF licenses this file
to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
"License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at
   
http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
   
Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
software distributed under the License is distributed on an
"AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
specific language governing permissions and limitations
under the License.
-->
<section xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="5.0" 
    xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook ../../../content/dtd/docbook.xsd"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    
    <title>BIRT Overview</title>
    <para>
        BIRT is an Eclipse-based open source reporting system for web applications,
        especially those based on Java and J2EE. BIRT has two main components: a report designer based on Eclipse,
        and a runtime component that you can add to your app server.
        BIRT also offers a charting engine that lets you add charts to your own application. 
    </para>
    <section>
        <title>With BIRT, you can add a rich variety of reports to your application.</title>
        <para>Lists - The simplest reports are lists of data. As the lists get longer,
            you can add grouping to organize related data together (orders grouped by customer,
            products grouped by supplier). If your data is numeric, you can easily add totals, averages and other summaries.</para>
        <para>Charts - Numeric data is much easier to understand when presented as a chart.
            BIRT provides pie charts, line &amp; bar charts and many more.
            BIRT charts can be rendered in SVG and support events to allow user interaction.</para>
        <para>Crosstabs - Crosstabs (also called a cross-tabulation or matrix) shows data in two dimensions: sales per quarter or hits per web page.</para>
        <para>Letters &amp; Documents - Notices, form letters, and other textual documents are easy to create with BIRT.
            Documents can include text, formatting, lists, charts and more.</para>
        <para>Compound Reports - Many reports need to combine the above into a single document.
            For example, a customer statement may list the information for the customer,
            provide text about current promotions, and provide side-by-side lists of payments and charges. A financial report may include disclaimers,
            charts, tables all with extensive formatting that matches corporate color schemes.</para>
    </section>
</section>