<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
or more contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file
distributed with this work for additional information
regarding copyright ownership.  The ASF licenses this file
to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
"License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
software distributed under the License is distributed on an
"AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
specific language governing permissions and limitations
under the License.
-->


<book version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
      xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
      xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>OFBiz Documentation</title>

    <author>
      <personname><firstname/><surname/></personname>

      <affiliation>
        <orgname/>
      </affiliation>
    </author>

    <pubdate/>
  </info>

  <chapter>
    <title>OFBiz Accounting Introduction</title>

    <para>The Accounting system is organized according to age old and
    generally accepted principles such as double-entry accounting, a General
    Ledger with hierarchical accounts, journals and posting of transactions
    and corresponding entries.</para>

    <para>The structure is primary based on the OMG GL standard and the work
    that was done on an AR/AP extension of the OMG GL standard. This
    correlates well with other standards such as ebXML and OAGIS.</para>

    <para>The Accounting entities are structured such that accounts for
    multiple organizations can be managed. The multiple organizations could be
    multiple companies, or departments or other organizations within a
    company. Each Organization can have various GL Accounts associated with it
    so that it can operate with its own subset of the Master Chart of
    Accounts.</para>

    <para>Each Organization can also have its own set of Journals for
    flexibility, even though the use of Journals should be as minimal as
    possible in favor of allowing the system to automatically create and post
    transactions based on business events triggered by standard procedures and
    documents such as purchase and sales orders, invoices, inventory
    transfers, payments, receipts, and so forth.</para>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="accounting_main">
    <title>Accounting Main</title>

    <screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata align="left"
                     fileref="../accounting_en_images/main.jpg"
                     scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>

    <para>This is the default tab for the Accounting Manager application. The
    screen currently shows links that will display more detailed screens
    related to Agreements, Billing Accounts, Invoices and Payments.</para>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="accounting_findInvoices">
    <title>Invoices</title>

    <para>Sales invoices are generated when customers buy something from your
    business. You will need to provide a detailed list of the items bought and
    relevant taxes paid. They are often referred to a 'tax invoices' as they
    contain information relating to the amount of sales tax (eg VAT / GST)
    charged on the product or service.</para>

    <para>Purchase invoices are generated by your suppliers when you order
    something from them. You may send them an order in the form of a Purchase
    Order. They will then send you the products and an invoice for payment.
    This invoice is the Purchase Invoice and it will contain details of the
    items bought plus any taxes.</para>

    <para>Both of these documents are used as proof to various tax authorities
    (eg Inland Revenue, Customs etc) that the required tax has been charged or
    collected.</para>

    <para>GENERAL NOTE: The following is an extract from Ian McNulty's
    documentation work on accounting:</para>

    <para>Invoices are created automatically by the system when certain
    criteria are met for each item on an order. The criteria will vary
    depending on the type of product associated with the order item, and the
    type of order (ie purchase/sales).</para>

    <para>For Sales Orders that include digital goods, an invoice will be
    created when the order is placed, and that invoice will be for all digital
    goods in the order. If there are non-digital or physical goods they will
    go in a separate invoice.</para>

    <para>For Sales Orders that include digital goods, an invoice will be
    created when the order is placed, and that invoice will be for all digital
    goods in the order. If there are non-digital or physical goods they will
    go in a separate invoice.</para>

    <para>For Purchase Orders an invoice will be created from a shipment when
    the shipment goes into the Received status.</para>

    <sect1>
      <title>Invoice Roles</title>

      <para>The Invoice Roles screen allows parties with specific roles to be
      associated with and invoice. If the e-commerce or Sales Order entry
      route has already been used then the invoice generated will already
      contain the relevant roles from the various parties.</para>

      <para>For a Sales Order examples of roles will include Bill From
      Customer, Bill To Customer, End User Customer,Ship To Customer
      etc.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I add a party role to an invoice?</title>

        <para>Party roles will automatically be added to an invoices that have
        been generated as a result of E-Commerce order entry or Sales Order
        entry. They can also be added be added manually.</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Roles' sub menu</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter or use the lookup to enter the party to be added to
            the invoice in the 'Party Id' field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter or use the lookup to enter the party to be added to
            the invoice in the 'Party Id' field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Date Time Performed' field blank<note>
                <para>This field is optional and can be entered if required.
                This field can be used to indicate the date and time this role
                was performed by the party for this invoice</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Percentage' field blank<note>
                <para>This field is optional and can be entered if required.
                If roles are shared then this field can be used to indicate
                the assigned percentage for this role</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The new role entry will be displayed on the bottom part of
            the screen <note>
                <para>If you select a role that is not associated with the
                party that has been entered an error message will be
                displayed. To fix it you will need to add the role to the
                party or choose another party that already has that role
                associated with it.</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update a party role on an invoice?</title>

        <para>A party role cannot be updated via the current user interface.
        It can only be removed. If a party role needs to be updated then the
        entry must be deleted and then re-created.</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I remove a party role from an invoice?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Locate the entry that needs to be removed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Locate the entry that needs to be removed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The entry is now removed from the list of invoice
            roles</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>New Invoice</title>

      <para>This screen allows the user to create a new Sales or Purchase
      Invoice. Sales Invoices are created when a customer buys something from
      you. Purchase Invoices are created when you buy something from a
      supplier.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I create a new Sales invoice?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Create New' button</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The New Sales Invoice / New Purchase Invoice screen is
            displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Using the top part of the screen, leave Invoice type with
            its default of 'Sales Invoice'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave 'Organization Party Id' with its default of
            'Company'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter or use the lookup to find the 'To Party Id' (eg
            DemoCustomer)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Create' button in the top part of the
            screen</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The invoice header has been created and the default header
            screen will be displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Details on the invoice will need to be entered via the other
            sub menus (eg Items, Time Entries etc)</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I create a new Purchase invoice?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Create New' button</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The New Sales Invoice / New Purchase Invoice screen is
            displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Using the bottom part of the screen, leave Invoice type with
            its default of 'Purchase Invoice'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave 'Organization Party Id' with its default of
            'Company'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter or use the lookup to find the 'From Party Id' (eg
            DemoSupplier)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Create' button in the bottom part of the
            screen</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The invoice header has been created and the default header
            screen will be displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Details on the invoice will need to be entered via the other
            sub menus (eg Items, Time Entries etc)</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Invoice Send Per Email</title>

      <para>This is used to send a copy of the invoice details to one or more
      email addresses. The invoice is included as an attachment and the user
      can add a simple accompanying email message.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I send a copy of an invoice via email?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Send per Email' sub menu</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Send per Email' default screen will be displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the 'From Email Address'<note>
                <para>CHECK: Shouldnt this be defaulted from the user
                login.....????</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'To Email Address' as it is as this will be
            defaulted using the customer details from the invoice</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>If required enter the 'Copy Email address' for anyone that
            needs to be copied on the email</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Subject' as the default of 'Please find attached
            invoice'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Other Currency' box blank<note>
                <para>CHECK: Investigate what effect this has on the
                email.....</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a short email message in the 'Email Body'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>List Invoice Items</title>

      <para>The Invoice Items screen displays the individual invoice line
      details and allows the user to update or remove an entry. As each
      invoice line is created it is allocated a specific sequence (or Item
      Number) which acts as a unique identifier.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I create a new invoice line item?</title>

        <para>Note that only invoices that have specific statuses can have new
        line items created. This means that if an invoice has already been
        paid and processed OFBiz will not allow any amendments to it.</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Items' sub menu for the invoice</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Add a new invoice item' screen will be displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Item No' field blank (as it will be automatically
            generated)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Invoice Item Type' from the drop down box<note>
                <para>A typical line using the demo could be 'Invoice Finished
                Good Item' but ensure that it corresponds with the type of
                products setup in your catalog</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a description describing what the line item is<note>
                <para>If you are going to enter a product in the Product Id
                field from the catalog then leave the 'Description' field
                blank as it will be used to show the product
                description</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Override GL Account Id' field blank as it will
            use the default account based on the Chart of Accounts
            setup</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Use the lookup or enter a product code in the 'Product Id'
            field<note>
                <para>This can be left blank if your invoice line is not
                related to a product in the catalog</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a number in the 'Quantity' field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a 'Unit Price' only if the Product Id field is
            blank<note>
                <para>If a Product Id has been entered then leave the 'Unit
                Price' field blank as it will pick up the product price from
                the catalog</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Inventory Item' field blank</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Product Feature Id' field blank</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'UOM' field blank</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Select 'Yes' for the 'Taxable Flag' field</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <note>
          <para>CHECK: Need to do some tests to see what line item type needs
          to be used for 'Sales Tax'. I think that it could be 'Invoice Item
          Sales Tax' since tax is currently calculated at invoice item line
          level. Also the automatically generated invoices from Order Entry
          and E-Commerce show taxes at the invoice item line level (think
          there may be some work going on - see JIRA on to consolidate
          entries). Need to do some tests using 'Invoice Sales Tax' to see how
          it works.........</para>
        </note>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update an invoice line item?</title>

        <para>Not all the fields on the invoice item line can be updated. For
        example Taxable Flag and Inventory Item cannot be updated. If these
        fields need to be amended then the invoice item will need to be
        removed and then re-created.</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Items' sub menu for the invoice</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Any existing line items will be displayed in the 'Items'
            box</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Amend the details in the line item that needs to be updated
            (eg Quantity, Invoice Item Type, Product Id, Description, Override
            GL Account, Unit Price)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Update' button displayed at the end of the line
            item that has been updated</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I delete an invoice item?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Items' sub menu for the invoice</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Any existing line items will be displayed in the 'Items'
            box</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Remove' button displayed at the end of the line
            item that needs to be deleted</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Edit Invoice Time Entries</title>

      <para>The Time Entries screen displays any time logged against the
      invoice. For example these time entries can be from employee or external
      supplier timesheets that are tracked within OFBiz. is used to track any
      individual work or billable hours against an invoice.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I add a new time entry for an invoice?</title>

        <para>There are two options :</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Add time entry to a new invoice and add time entry to an
            existing invoice.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Add time entry to a new invoice and add time entry to an
            existing invoice.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update a time entry for an invoice?</title>

        <note>
          <para>To check if this can only be done via timesheets.</para>
        </note>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I remove a time entry from an invoice?</title>

        <note>
          <para>To check if this is done via timesheets</para>
        </note>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Edit Invoice Applications</title>

      <para>The Invoice Applications sub menu is where payments that have been
      made (or received) can be linked or allocated to an invoice. The phrase
      'applying' an amount to an invoice is often used to describe this. The
      screen is divided into 3 main areas as follows.</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Payments Applied (which shows details of the total amount
          'Applied' and the total amount 'Open'. Note that 'Open' here means
          outstanding)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Possible Payments to Apply (which shows all the payments that
          have been sent from the same party id as the invoice - for a sales
          invoice this would be the customer party id)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Assign Payment to Invoice (which allows you to manually assign
          a specific payment id to this invoice)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <note>
        <para>General Ledger accounting transactions are generated during the
        payment application process but unless your GL is setup with Unapplied
        Cash and Applied Cash accounts - I'm not sure that there will be any
        true accounting impact. In the Sales Order process the accounting
        transaction generated the following GL Accounting transaction is
        generated for 'Payment Applied' o add some text here.</para>
      </note>

      <para>DR 120000 Accounts Receivable / CR 120000 Accounts Receivable -
      This transaction doesnt really do anything!</para>

      <para>It is used to link payments to invoices. It is also used to
      allocate which part of a payment is allocated or applied to a specific
      invoice. This is extremely useful if your customers pay multiple
      invoices with a single payment.</para>

      <para>Example:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>A customer could send a single payment of $1000 that can be
          used to pay for two invoices (eg $400 and $600)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Using this applications sub menu allows you to allocate part
          of the $400 to one invoice and the balance ($600) to the other
          invoice</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>By default all 'unapplied' payments that have been entered into
      OFBiz from the customer will be available for selection even if they
      have not yet been flagged as formally 'Received'. This means that these
      are payments that have not already been linked to another invoice. If
      only part of a payment amount has been linked to an invoice then the
      remaining amount is left available to be allocated to another invoice.
      Also note that a single invoice could be paid by multiple payments being
      applied to it.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I apply a payment (or payments) to an invoice?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Applications' sub menu for the invoice</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>A list of unapplied payments for the party id will be
            displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>A list of unapplied payments for the party id will be
            displayed<note>
                <para>More than one entry may be used. Also only part of a
                larger amount may be used)The Payments Applied total at the
                top of the screen will be updated with the amount selected.
                Also the Amount Open will be reduced by the amount
                selected.</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>More than one entry may be used. Also only part of a larger
            amount may be used)The Payments Applied total at the top of the
            screen will be updated with the amount selected. Also the Amount
            Open will be reduced by the amount selected.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>More than one entry may be used. Also only part of a larger
            amount may be used)The Payments Applied total at the top of the
            screen will be updated with the amount selected. Also the Amount
            Open will be reduced by the amount selected.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update an applied payment for an invoice?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Payments that have been applied to an invoice can be
            updated. This means that you can change the details of the payment
            transaction or adjust the amount that was applied to the
            invoice.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Applications' sub menu for the invoice</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>A list of payments already applied to the invoice will be
            displayed in the top part of the screen</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter or use the lookup to change the 'Payment Id' if
            required</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the updated amount in the 'Amount to Apply' field if
            required</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Update' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I remove an applied payment (or payments) from an
        invoice?</title>

        <note>
          <para>CHECK: It can be done before transaction has been posted to GL
          but also need to check if its can be done if the transaction has
          been posted.</para>
        </note>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Applications' sub menu for the invoice</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Applications' sub menu for the invoice</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the payment entry that
            needs to be removed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The entry will be removed and the top part of the screen
            will be update the 'Payments Applied' total and 'Amount
            Open'</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Edit Invoice</title>

      <para>The Invoice Header screen is used to view or update details from
      the invoice header. Examples of the type of information that can be
      changed are Due Date, Description, Currency.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update the header details for an Invoice?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Header' sub menu and the header details of the
            invoice will be displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Update the fields required</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Update' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Invoice Overview</title>

      <para>The Invoice Overview screen is used to display the summary of an
      invoice in a single view. The screen is divided into sections that show
      various information related to the invoice (eg Roles, Status, Terms,
      Items, Payments Applied, etc).</para>

      <para>The following options are currently available from this
      screen:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The following options are currently available from this
          screen:</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Copy (Create a copy of the current invoice)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>PDF (View a PDF of the current invoice)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>PDF default currency<note>
              <para>CHECK: Need to see how this is different from just the PDF
              view......</para>
            </note></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Status to 'Approved' (Change the status of the current invoice
          to 'Approved)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Status to 'Sent' (Change the status of the current invoice to
          'Sent')</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Status to 'Ready' (Change the status of the current invoice to
          'Ready'.<note>
              <para>This will create the relevant accounting transactions and
              post them to the general ledger</para>
            </note></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Status to 'Cancelled' (Change the status of the current
          invoice to 'Cancelled')</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Save as Template (NOTE TO CHECK: Save the current invoice
          format as a template)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Find Invoices</title>

      <para>The default screen is for the Invoices tab is 'Find Invoices'. It
      is used to locate existing invoices that have been created automatically
      by the system or manually by the user. It can also be used to create a
      new Sales or Purchase Invoice.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I view all invoices?</title>

        <para>Press the 'Search' button to view all invoices</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I locate an existing invoice?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the 'Invoice ID' if known</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a word from the invoice description in the
            'Description' field if known</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the 'Invoice Type' if known</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the 'From Party Id' if known<note>
                <para>In most cases for a Sales Invoices this will be Company.
                For Purchase Invoice it will be the supplier party id</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the 'Billing Account Id' if known</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the invoice status in the 'Status Id' field if
            known</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the 'To Party Id' if known<note>
                <para>In most cases for a Purchase Invoice this will be
                company. For Sales Invoices it will be the customer party
                id</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Search' button to view all invoices</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>All invoices that meet the search criteria will be
            displayed.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update an invoice?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Locate the invoice using the 'Find Invoices' screen</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Using the relevant sub menu make the required
            changes.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I delete an invoice?</title>

        <para>Invoices cannot be deleted through the user interface. They can
        only be cancelled (eg if they have been entered or created by
        mistake). <note>
            <para>They can probably be deleted using Entity Data Maintenance
            in the Webtools menu but this is not recommended for 2
            reasons:<orderedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>It may cause data integrity problems.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>It may cause data integrity problems.</para>
                </listitem>
              </orderedlist></para>
          </note></para>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="accounting_findPayments">
    <title>Payments</title>

    <para>This feature lets the user locate payments by common
    criteria.</para>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="accounting_FindPaymentGroup">
    <title>Payment Group</title>

    <para>Find payments by group.</para>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="accounting_FindGatewayResponses">
    <title>Transactions</title>

    <para/>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="accounting_FindPaymentGatewayConfig">
    <title>Payment Gateway Config</title>

    <para/>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="accounting_FindBillingAccount">
    <title>Billing Accounts</title>

    <para>A billing account is a way of allowing customers to consolidate
    several invoices into an account that is paid off at a later
    date.Customers can be allocated a credit limit and orders can be taken up
    to the value of the credit limit without any payment being made.
    Statements to the customer can then be generated (eg monthly) and payment
    is made based on the outstanding amount.</para>

    <note>
      <para>A billing account does not change the flow of the normal Invoice
      and Payment processes. It simply allows for a more structured
      organisation of Invoices and Payments.</para>
    </note>

    <para>Billing Accounts can be used for the following:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Setting credit limits for customers</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Keeping track of credit available to customer for purchase on
        account</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Keeping track of payments made in advance <note>
            <para>Could also use Financial Account for advance payments but
            need to understand the differences in functionality and
            process</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Keeping track of a subset of payments and invoices for a
        specific client, i.e. allowing them to have multiple billing
        accounts.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Allow multiple authorised parties to bill against the same
        account which one party is responsible for paying (e.g. different
        offices of the same organisation may have one single account with a
        supplier to make use of order volume discounts)</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Managing and generating customer statements</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Customer specific order tracking</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Accounts Receivable / Debt Management</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Analysis and monitoring customer spending (creditworthiness /
        discounts / product popularity)</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <note>
      <para>A payment that is applied (or matched) to a Billing Account it
      should still be applied to an invoice. In the case where the payment
      arrives before the invoice has been generated then once the invoice is
      generated it should be applied to the payment or payments.</para>
    </note>

    <sect1>
      <title>Billing Account Orders</title>

      <para>This sub menu lists the details of any Sales Orders that have been
      charged to the billing account. A Sales Order is charged to a billing
      account by selecting the billing account as the Payment Method. <note>
          <para>The details displayed here in conjunction with the 'Payments'
          sub menu could also be used to generate a customer statement or
          account showing details of customer activity during a specified time
          period.</para>
        </note></para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Billing Account Payments</title>

      <para>This sub menu allows the creation of a payment that is
      automatically applied to the billing account.</para>

      <para>It is used when a payment has been received from a customer that
      is used to pay off the balance (or part balance) of a billing
      account.</para>

      <para>An example of how this works is similar to a credit card statement
      where a list of transactions have been incurred over the previous month
      and one payment is used to settle the outstanding balance.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I add a payment to a billing account?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Payments' sub menu</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Create Payment' screen is displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter or use the lookup to enter the 'From Party Id' (NOTE:
            By default this will be the Bill To Party of the Billing
            Account)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Organisation Party Id' from the drop down
            box</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Payment Type Id' from the drop down box (NOTE:
            By default this will be set to 'Customer Deposit')</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Payment Method Type' as 'Billing Account' (NOTE
            TO CHECK: What happens if you do change this....)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the 'Amount' of the payment</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Create' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>The new entry is displayed at the bottom of the screen.<note>
            <para>The total amount of the payment will be applied to the
            Billing Account. This can be verified by going to Accounting /
            Payments menu and locating the newly created payment. The 'Amount
            to Apply' column will be zero.</para>
          </note></para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update a payment for a billing account?</title>

        <para>A payment can be updated for a billing account by amending the
        amount of the payment that has been applied to the billing account.
        For example if a payment of $100 has been applied to a billing account
        it can be amended so that only $75 will be applied and $25 will be
        available to be applied elsewhere.</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Click on the 'Payment Id' of the payment that needs to be
            removed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Payment Overview' screen is displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Update' button in the 'Payments Applied'
            box</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Payment Applications' screen is displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Locate the 'Billing Account Id' and 'Amount Applied'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Amend the 'Amount Applied' for the billing account</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Update' button next to the entry that refers to
            the 'Billing Account Id'</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>A message will be displayed saying that the payment has been
        removed from the billing account</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I delete a payment from a billing account?</title>

        <para>A payment can be removed from billing account by removing the
        link that has applied the payment to the billing account.<orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Click on the 'Payment Id' of the payment that needs to be
              removed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Payment Overview' screen is displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Update' button in the 'Payments Applied'
              box</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Payment Applications' screen is displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the entry that refers to
              the 'Billing Account Id'</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist></para>

        <para>A message will be displayed saying that the payment has been
        removed from the billing account<note>
            <para>The above example was done when the payment status was at
            'Not Paid' - need to test if it still works if the payment status
            is at 'Received' or 'Confirmed' too.</para>
          </note></para>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Billing Account Invoices</title>

      <para>The Billing Account Find Invoices screen displays by default a
      list of invoices that have been charged to the billing account.</para>

      <para>Any invoice displayed here means that its invoice amount has been
      deducted from the billing account credit limit.For example: If the
      Billing Account Credit Limit is $100 and the there are 2 invoices
      displayed with amounts $10 and $25 then the available credit for the
      billing account will be $75.</para>

      <para>The invoice can be at various statues and there is an option to
      locate an invoice by status.</para>

      <para>It is also used to apply any payments that have been made into the
      Billing Account to an invoice. A 'Capture' button is displayed next to
      each invoice displayed that has an amount outstanding.</para>

      <para>Example:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Two invoices are charged to a Billing Account (Invoice A $10
          and Invoice B $25)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>A payment of $17 has been paid into the Billing Account</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>If the Capture button is pressed for the invoice A then $10 of
          the $17 payment will be applied to this invoice and a new payment
          transaction of $7 will be created and available to apply to a
          different invoice</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I locate an invoice by status?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Invoices' sub menu</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Use the drop down box to select the 'Status Id' for the
            invoice required</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>A list of invoices with the required status will be
        displayed</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I capture a payment for an invoice?</title>

        <para><important>
            <para>In order for this to work a payment needs to have been made
            to the billing account that has not been completely applied to any
            other invoices. Payments to a billing account can be done via the
            'Payments' sub menu for the billing account or by using Accounting
            / Payments menu.</para>
          </important></para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Invoices' sub menu</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Locate the invoice required <note>
                <para>The 'Amount to Apply' is the same as the 'Total'
                column</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Capture' button <note>
                <para>The 'Amount to Apply' is different to the 'Total'
                column</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>The 'Capture' button is no longer displayed next to the invoice
        and an additional payments transaction will be created for any
        difference between the invoice total and the amount paid (Eg Invoice
        Total $100, Payment Amount $125, the new payment transaction amount
        will be $25)<note>
            <para>The above example assumes that the payment available will
            cover the total amount outstanding for the invoice</para>
          </note></para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title/>

        <para/>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Billing Account Terms</title>

      <para>This sub menu allows terms to be associated with a billing
      account. Currently these can be the following:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>payment terms (discounted if paid within specified
          days)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>payment terms (due on a specified day per month)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>payment terms (net days)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>penalty terms (late fee)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>penalty terms (collection agency fee)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>miscellaneous (non returnable sales item)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <note>
        <para>There is an overlap here with the terms that can be specified in
        an agreement. Would a billing account party also have an agreement for
        payment terms...? .</para>
      </note>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I add terms to a billing account?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Terms' sub menu</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Select a 'Term Type' from the drop down box (eg. Payment net
            days)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'UOM' field blank</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a number in the 'Term Value' field (eg. 30 which would
            mean '30 days' when related to 'Payment net days')</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Save' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>The term is displayed in the top part of the screen</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update terms for a billing account?</title>

        <para>Select the 'Terms' sub menu<orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Edit' button next to the entry that needs to be
              amended</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The details are displayed in the 'Edit Billing Account
              Terms' box</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Update the 'Term Type', 'UOM' or 'Term Value' as
              required</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Save' button</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist></para>

        <para>The updated term is displayed in the top part of the
        screen</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I remove terms from a billing account?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Terms' sub menu</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Delete' button next to the entry that needs to be
            removed</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Billing Account Roles</title>

      <para>This sub menu allows parties with specific roles to be associated
      with to a Billing Account. Roles allows you to specify a party
      role.</para>

      <para>It is used to specify which party should be billed for the billing
      account. It can be used as follows:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Simple billing account for a single party</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>More complex billing account where multiple parties (eg
            company subsidiaries) charge invoices to the billing account but a
            different party (eg head office) will pay the account</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I add a party role to a billing account?</title>

        <para>Select the 'Roles' sub menu</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter or use the lookup to select the 'Party Id'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Role Type Id' from the drop down box (eg Bill To
            Customer)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'From Date' blank (NOTE: If left blank it will
            default to the current date and time)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Thru Date' blank</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Add' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>The new party role is displayed at the bottom of the
        screen</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update a party role for a billing account?</title>

        <para>The only field that can be updated for a party role is the 'Thru
        Date'. If any other details need to be amended then the entry will
        need to be deleted and then recreated.</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Roles' sub menu</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Locate the entry that needs to be amended</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter or use the lookup to enter the 'Thru Date'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Update' button for the entry</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I delete a party role from a billing account?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Locate the entry that needs to be deleted</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Delete' button next to the entry</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The entry will be removed from the bottom of the
            screen</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Edit Billing Account</title>

      <para>The 'Account' sub menu is used to enter the basic details required
      for setting up a new billing account or editing an existing one.</para>

      <para>It can be used to create or update the following details for a
      Billing Account:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Billing Account Identification</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Party to be Billed</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Billing Account Limit (NOTE: This is how much credit the
          customer will be given eg $5000)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Currency to be used for Billing Account</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Start and End Dates</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <note>
        <para>There are currently two ways to add a party to a billing
        account.</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a party id in the 'Party Billed To' field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Use the 'Roles' sub menu to add a party id with the role of
            'Bill To Customer'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>If using the first method then when you press the update
            button this removes the party id from this field and automatically
            creates the party under the Roles sub menu with the role of 'Bill
            To Customer'</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </note>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I create a new Billing Account?</title>

        <para>Example: To create a new Billing Account</para>

        <note>
          <para>Check if the party doesnt have the role 'Bill To Customer' is
          it automatically added when the billing account is created or will
          the creation fail?..</para>
        </note>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'New' button and the 'Edit Billing Account' screen
            is displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a code or number for the 'Billing Account Id'<note>
                <para>If this is left blank a number will be automatically
                generated</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a number for the 'Billing Account Limit' (eg
            5000)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Account Currency UOM Id' as it is <note>
                <para>This should be the default currency for
                Company...</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a description that can be used to identify the Billing
            Account (eg Joe Bloggs Builders Billing Account)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Contact Mech' field as it is<note>
                <para>This field cannot be filled in until either the 'Party
                Billed To' has been filled in or a party with the role of
                'Bill To Customer' has been added under the 'Roles' sub
                menu.</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the Billing Account start date in the 'From Date'
            field. <note>
                <para>If left blank then this will default to the current date
                and time. NOTE TO CHECK: Can this date be in the
                future.....?</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Thru date' field blank</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter or use the lookup to select the 'Party Billed
            To'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Update' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>After the 'Update' button has been pressed then the 'Contact
        Mech Id' field will either be automatically filled in or will allow
        you to select a contact mech from a drop down list</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update an existing Billing Account?</title>

        <para>Billing Account details can be updated. A key field that may
        need to be updated is the actual Billing Account Limit if a customer
        reduces or improves their credit rating</para>

        <para>Example: To Update a Billing Account</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Click on the 'Billing Account Id' of the Billing Account to
            updated</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Edit Billing Account' screen is displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the changes required</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Update' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I delete a Billing Account?</title>

        <para>Billing Accounts cannot be deleted. They can only be expired.
        This means that they will no longer be able to be used to associate
        invoices or payments against.</para>

        <para>Example: To Expire a Billing Account</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Click on the 'Billing Account Id' of the Billing Account to
            be expired</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Edit Billing Account' screen is displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the current date in the 'Thru date' field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Update' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Find Billing Account</title>

      <para>The default screen is for the Billing Account tab is 'Find Billing
      Account'. It is used to locate existing billing accounts that have been
      created.</para>

      <para>The user has the option to select an existing billing account or
      create a new one by clicking on the 'New' button.</para>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="accounting_FinAccountMain">
    <title>Financial Account</title>

    <para>A financial account is a tool (similar to bank account statement)
    that is used for monitoring monetary transactions. Normally they will be
    linked to a party and the various transactions details (eg payments or
    receipts) will be shown as entries.</para>

    <para>The entries for a financial account can be displayed using the
    'Financial Account' tab in Accounting or in Party Manager if you enter a
    party as the owner of the financial account.</para>

    <para>Currently in OFBiz financial accounts can have the following
    types:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Bank Account (by default this type will post to 213500 CUSTOMER
        DEPOSIT ACCOUNTS)</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Deposit Account (by default this type will post to 213500
        CUSTOMER DEPOSIT ACCOUNTS)</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Gift Certificate (by default this type will post to 213200 GIFT
        CERTIFICATES UNREDEEMED)</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Investment Account (by default this type will post to 213500
        CUSTOMER DEPOSIT ACCOUNTS)</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Replenish Account (no default posting account in demo data
        setup)</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Service Credit Account (no default posting account in demo data
        setup)</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <note>
      <para>:</para>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>In GL Account Defaults there is a specific tab 'FinAccount
          Type Gl Account' for specifying which type of Financial accounts are
          posted to which general ledger account.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>In GL Account Defaults there is also a tab 'Payment Method Id
          / GL Account ID' for specifying the account to post transactions to
          if 'Financial Account' is selected as the Payment Method instead of
          (Cash, Cheque, Credit Card, etc). By default the demo setup posts
          transactions to 111100 GENERAL CHECKING ACCOUNT.</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </note>

    <para>You can also setup each financial account to post to a specific
    general ledger account for each party. This is done via a specific field
    during the creation or update of a financial account. This will override
    the default setting by type.</para>

    <para>Financial Accounts can be used for the following</para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Managing and Tracking Customer Prepaid Accounts</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Managing and Tracking Customer Credit Limit <note>
            <para>Need to verify this</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Managing Electronic Gift Certificates / Gift Vouchers/ Gift
        Card</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Reload of Electronic Gift Card</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Company Bank Account Transaction Tracking</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <sect1>
      <title>Financial Account Main Screen</title>

      <para>The default screen for Financial Accounts displays a list of any
      bank accounts that have been created. Details listed include the account
      the following:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>account name</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>organisation the account is linked to</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>account balances (available and actual)</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Find Financial Account Reconciliations</title>

      <para>This screen displays the details of any reconciliations in
      progress for a financial account. Only reconciliations that have actual
      transactions associated with them will be displayed. If a reconciliation
      group has no transactions assigned to it then it will not be
      displayed.</para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>View GL Reconciliation</title>

      <para>This screen gives an overview of a reconciliation group / bank
      reconciliation. Note that a reconciliation must have at least one
      transaction associated with it for this screen to be displayed. It is
      used as follows:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>to view transactions associated with a reconciliation group /
          bank reconciliation</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>to remove transactions from a reconciliation group / bank
          reconciliation</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>to reconcile the reconciliation group / bank
          reconciliation</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>The screen displays the current reconciliation details plus
      details of the previous reconciliation if one exists. This ensures the
      closing balance of the previous reconciliation is the same as the
      opening balance for the current one.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I edit reconciliation?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Edit' button in the 'Current Bank
            Reconciliation'part of the screen</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Edit Financial Account Reconciliations' screen
            isdisplayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Update the details required</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Update' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I remove a transaction from a bank
        reconciliation?</title>

        <para>On the lower part of the screen a list of all transactions
        associated with the reconciliation is displayed.</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the entry that needs to be
            removed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The transaction is removed</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I reconcile a bank reconciliation?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>A total of all transactions associated with the
            reconciliation is shown in the lower part of the screen</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Reconcile' button next to the total</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Each transaction status will be changed to 'Approved' and
            the reconciliation / bank reconciliation status will be changed to
            'Reconciled'<note>
                <para>This means that no new transactions can be added to this
                reconciliation and it will no longer be available to assign
                transactions to</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Edit Financial Account Reconciliations</title>

      <para>This screen is used to create or update a reconciliation group /
      bank reconciliation. The following details can be input or updated for
      the reconciliation:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>GL Reconciliation Name or Identifier</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Description for the reconciliation</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Organisation Party Id for the reconciliation</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Opening Balance for the reconciliation</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Reconciliation date</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Deposit Slips</title>

      <para>This section describes how to create, find, and edit deposit
      slips.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>New Deposit Slip</title>

        <para>This screen allows the user to create an Payment Group and the
        transactions associated with the Payment Group will generate a deposit
        slip. .</para>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I create a New Deposit Slip?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Find' button to list all the available
              transactions</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select the transactions to include in the Payment Group by
              using the 'Select All' or the check box that corresponds to the
              transactions required</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter a 'Payment Group Name' if required (If none is
              entered then by default this will be 'Payment Group
              Name')</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Create Batch' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>A button to print the deposit slip will be displayed as
              well as the edit screen to make any further changes to the
              Payment Batch</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Find Deposit Slips</title>

        <para>This screen is used to locate payment groups and their
        associated deposit slips that have been created. Deposit slips are
        created by grouping transactions together into a Payment Group. This
        can be done using the 'Accounting / Payment Group' tab, the 'Financial
        Account / Deposit Withdraw' tab or the 'Create New Deposit Slip'
        button.</para>

        <para>Currently Deposit Slips are created for AR Batch Payments
        only.</para>

        <para>The deposit slips are available in PDF format and there is an
        option to cancel the batch that generated the deposit slip if
        required.</para>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I locate an existing Deposit Slip?</title>

          <para>Enter some characters from the 'Payment Group Id' or 'Payment
          Group Name' if known</para>

          <para>Press the 'Search' button</para>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I update an existing Deposit Slip?</title>

          <para><orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Locate the Payment Group required</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the Payment Group by clicking on the Payment
                Group Id</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>The 'Edit Payment Group' screen is displayed Add any
          new payment deposits or update existing deposits for the Payment
          Group All changes in the Payment Group will automatically be updated
          to the Deposit Slip</para>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I delete an existing Deposit Slip?</title>

          <para>A deposit slip can not be directly deleted but it is removed
          when a Payment Group is cancelled Press the 'Cancel' button next to
          the Payment Group required to cancel a payment group The Payment
          Group is removed from the 'Find Deposits' screen and no deposit
          slips can be viewed or printed.</para>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Edit Deposit Slip</title>

        <para>This screen displays the details of a Payment Group and its
        transactions. The Deposit Slip for the Payment Group can be printed if
        required and the Payment Group itself can be updated. Details that can
        be updated include the name of the Payment Group itself and the
        addition, removal or update of transactions.</para>

        <note>
          <para>Any changes to the Payment Group will be automatically updated
          to the Deposit Slip.</para>
        </note>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I update a Deposit Slip?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select the Payment Group required</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Update the 'Payment Group Name' if required</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Use the lookup for 'Payment Id' to add new transactions to
              the Payment Group if required</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Use the 'Cancel' button next to a particular transaction
              to remove it from the Payment Group</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Update' or 'Add' buttons as required</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Print Deposit Slip' button</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>

          <para>The Deposit Slip will be displayed with the latest details of
          the transactions for the Payment Group</para>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Financial Account Deposit / Withdraw</title>

      <para>By default this screen will display all payment transactions both
      incoming and outgoing that have not already been associated with a
      financial account that represents one of the company's bank
      accounts.</para>

      <para>This screen also gives the option to create new deposit or
      withdrawal payments. The user can select a number of incoming deposit
      payments (eg Customer Payments etc) and group them together into a
      payment group (i.e AR Batch of Payments) that will create a 'deposit
      slip'.</para>

      <para>If you select a number of incoming payments and dont group them
      then no payment group is created (and therefore not deposit slip either)
      but the individual transactions will be created for the 'bank account'
      financial account.</para>

      <para>Note that outgoing payments cannot be grouped together and will
      not create a 'deposit slip'.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I list Deposit or Withdrawal Payments not linked to a
        Bank Account?</title>

        <para>Press the 'Find' button on the 'Deposit/Withdraw' screen.</para>

        <para>All deposit and withdrawal transactions not associated with a
        bank 'financial account' will be displayed.</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I group payments and create a deposit slip?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Press 'Find' to list all Deposit or Withdrawal
            payments</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Use the 'Select All' or click on the check box associated
            with the transactions required</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a name for the Payment Party Group Name (eg XYZ
            Deposits) to group the transactions together</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Deposit/Withdraw' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>A deposit will be created that can be viewed under the 'Deposit
        Slip' tab and grouped transaction will be created under the
        'Transactions' tab with a link to the deposit slip breakdown</para>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Financial Account Authorizations</title>

      <para>An authorization is a temporary transaction showing a commitment
      to take money from a financial account. It is like a 'transaction in
      progress' where there can be delay between when you buy something and
      the time it actually appears on your statement.</para>

      <para>Authorizations can be time limit specific meaning that they can be
      controlled by entering a start and end date so that they are only valid
      for a certain length of time. They can also be expired. When an
      authorization is expired it removes the commitment from the financial
      account. The history of expired authorizations are shown on the
      financial account.</para>

      <note>
        <para>This could be very useful in ensuring that customers are not
        overcommitted and keeping within their approved credit limits.</para>
      </note>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I add an authorization?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter an amount in the 'Amount' field (Eg 1000)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Currency' field blank as the default currency
            will be used</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a date in the 'Authorisation Date' field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'From Date' field blank</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Thru Date' field blank</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Add' button<note>
                <para>When you now view the Financial Account detail the
                'Actual Balance' and 'Available Balance' fields will be
                different.</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update an authorization?</title>

        <para>An authorization cannot be updated. It can only be expired. If
        you have made a mistake and need to change an authorization then it
        needs to expired and then re-created correctly.</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I delete an authorization?</title>

        <para>Authorizations are not deleted they are instead expired. This
        means that the history of the authorizations will remain on the
        account as an audit trail.</para>

        <para>Example: To expire an authorisation</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Authorizations' tab for the Financial
            Account</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Any authorizations will be displayed at the bottom of the
            screen</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>If the authorization is still current the 'Thru Date' field
            will be blank<note>
                <para>CHECK: May not always be true as you can specify a
                future date for it to expire......!!!</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Expire' button next to the authorisation to be
            expired</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>The authorization is removed from the financial account and the
        screen is redisplayed with the 'Thru Date' field completed</para>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Find Financial Account Transactions</title>

      <para>A transaction is an entry that is shown on the financial account.
      Transactions can be one of the following types:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Deposits</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Withdrawals</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Adjustments</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Transactions are used to show entries and the financial history of
      the financial account. Similar to a bank account or credit card
      statement the transaction will show details of what was spent or paid
      into the account.</para>

      <para>Some transaction totals have been added to this screen to help as
      part of the reconciliation processes. Additional details available
      include number of transactions, transaction totals and status.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I find transactions for a Financial Account?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Search' button</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>A list of transactions for the financial account will be
            displayed</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Financial Account Bank Reconciliation</title>

        <para>Bank Reconciliation is a regular task where transactions from
        the company bank statement are matched against transactions that have
        occurred in the General Ledger. This is done based on a specific
        date(NOTE: This can be done daily, weekly but is usually an end of
        month). A specific GL account is normally used to represent the
        company bank account and any accounting transaction that involves the
        bank account will automatically record and entry in the GL</para>

        <para>The bank reconciliation process ensures that the GL account and
        the bank statement reconcile to the same amounts. Differences can
        occur between the GL and the bank statement for a variety of valid
        reasons including the following:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Payments or Deposits in process (especially cheques)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Interest or Bank Charges that are not known in advance but
            are applied to the bank account</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Currency or Exchange Rate variations / charges</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Any outstanding</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <note>
          <para>The differences will occur because of timing differences of
          when and how transactions are recorded. Examples are as
          follows:</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Bank charges are known to the bank first and only once
              they have applied the charge to the bank account can the company
              duplicate the transaction in the GL to make the balance
              reconcile.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>A customer cheque payment may be recorded in the GL first
              before it is paid into the bank account</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </note>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I create a Bank Reconciliation?</title>

          <para>The bank reconciliation process is made up of 3 steps.</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Creating an account reconciliation group</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Assigning transactions to the reconciliation</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Validating the figures and confirming the
              reconciliation</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I create an account reconciliation group for Bank
          Reconciliation?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Go to the Financial Account 'Reconciliation' sub menu for
              the bank account to be reconciled</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Create New Financial Account Reconciliations'
              button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Complete the details (eg name, description, organisation
              and opening balance) required on the 'Add New Financial Account
              Reconciliations' screen and press the 'Create' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The new account reconciliation group is created and may be
              used to assign transactions to</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I locate transactions that have not been assigned to a
          Bank Reconciliation?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Go to the Financial Account 'Transactions' sub menu of the
              bank account to be reconciled</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Find Transactions For Financial Account: XXXX' is
              displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Use the dropdown box for 'GL Reconciliation Id' field to
              select 'Not Assigned' and then press the 'Search' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>A list of transactions (deposits, withdrawals or
              adjustments) that have not been reconciled will be displayed
              (NOTE: If no transactions are displayed then there are no
              transactions to reconcile)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Click on the 'check box' at the end of the transaction
              line that corresponds to the entry that needs to be assigned
              (NOTE:More than one transaction can be selected at a
              time)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Above the 'check box' is the 'Assign to Reconciliation'
              button and to the left of this is a dropdown box to select the
              reconciliation that the transaction is to be assigned to.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Using the drop down box select the reconciliation required
              and press the 'Assign to Reconciliation' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The transaction is removed from the 'Not Assigned' status
              and added to the specified reconciliation group</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I validate and confirm the Bank
          Reconciliation?</title>

          <para>Validation can be done for individual transactions or for the
          complete account reconciliation group. The user controls this by the
          search criteria entered on this screen.</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Go to the 'Transactions' sub menu for the bank account and
              press the 'Bank Reconciliation' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select the 'GL Reconciliation Id' that is to be
              reconciled</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Click on the 'Select All' check box on the right hand side
              of the screen. (NOTE: All transactions in this group will be
              reconciled)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Reconcile' button above the 'Select All' check
              box</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I view a Bank Reconciliation?</title>

          <para>Once all the transactions in a reconciliation group have been
          reconciled then the status of the group is changed to 'Reconciled'.
          This means that no new transactions can be added to the is group and
          the reconciled balance is fixed.</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Go to the 'Reconciliation' sub menu for the bank
              account</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>A list of all the bank reconciliation groups are displayed
              with details of the status (eg Created or Reconciled)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Click on the 'GL Reconciliation Id' of the group and the
              details are displayed</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I cancel a Bank Reconciliation?</title>

          <para>If a bank reconciliation needs to be cancelled due to a
          mistake or error then the bank reconciliation can be cancelled as
          long as it has not been fully reconciled (i.e. the status of the
          reconciliation has not been changed to 'Reconciled'. This will allow
          you to start the bank reconcilation again.</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Go to the 'Reconciliation' sub menu for the bank
              account</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>A list of all the bank reconciliation groups are displayed
              (NOTE: If no transactions are associated with a reconciliation
              group then it will not be displayed here)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Click on the 'Cancel' button associated with the 'GL
              Reconciliation Id' of the group that needs to be
              cancelled</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>All transactions will be removed from the reconciliation
              group and their status will be changed back to 'Not Assigned' so
              that they can be re-assigned to this or any other
              reconciliation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Edit Financial Account Transactions</title>

        <para><emphasis role="bold">How do I add transactions to a financial
        account?</emphasis></para>

        <para>An example of how to bring in an opening balance is shown
        below:</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Navigate to the the Financial Account Transactions sub
            menu</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Select 'Adjustment' in the Fin Account Trans Type Id
            field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Party Id' field blank</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Fill in the 'Transaction Date' field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Fill in the 'Entry Date' field<note>
                <para>CHECK: This could be useful in identifying transactions
                to a greater level of detail....</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Fill in the 'Amount' field with the transaction amount (Eg.
            In our case this is the opening balance such as 353.88 - dont
            think we need the $ sign)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Payment Id' field blank</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Order Id' field blank</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Order Item Seq Id' field blank</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Reason Enum Id' field blank<note>
                <para>CHECK: This could be useful in identifying transactions
                to a greater level of detail....</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Fill in the 'Comments' field (Eg: Opening Balance from XYZ
            Statement)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Add' button and the transaction will be displayed
            at the bottom of the screen</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <note>
          <para>When you now view the Financial Account detail the 'Actual
          Balance' and 'Available Balance' fields will show the entered
          opening balance (eg 353.88)</para>
        </note>

        <para><emphasis role="bold">Other ways to add transactions to a
        financial account?</emphasis></para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>By selecting financial account as a payment method for a
            customer</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>By selecting financial account as a refund method for a
            customer</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Edit Financial Account Roles</title>

      <para>The Financial Account Roles sub menu screen allows you specify a
      party and link them to a role for a particular financial account.</para>

      <para>It can be used to add party roles eg 'Approver' or 'Administrator'
      for credit limits or updates to the account. If an account belongs to a
      company then you may want to add a person as a 'Contact' for dealing
      with the account.</para>

      <para>The roles can also be time bound. This means that you can specify
      a start and end date for the party role.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I add a Party Role to a Financial Account?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select the 'Roles' sub menu for the Financial Account</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Fill in the Party Id field by using the field lookup tool or
            by directly entering the party id (eg flexadmin)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Select the role from the drop down list for the Role Type Id
            field (eg administrator)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the From Date field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter if the Thru Date field (optional)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Add' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Create / Edit Financial Account</title>

      <para>This screen allows the user to create a new financial account or
      to edit an existing one.</para>

      <para>The 'Financial Account' submenu is the first of four submenus used
      in the creation or update of a Financial Account. On the creation or
      update of a Financial Account it is the default screen that is
      displayed.</para>

      <para>It can be used for updating the basic details of a Financial
      account such as:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Type of Account (eg Deposit, Investment, Gift
          Certificate)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Account Status (Active, Frozen, Cancel, etc)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Account Name and Code</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Currency</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Owner Party ID</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Default GL Account for Posting</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Replenishment Level</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I create a new Financial Account?</title>

        <para>Select the 'Create New Financial Account' button from the 'Find
        Financial Accounts' screen</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Create/Update Financial Account' screen is
            displayed.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Keep the default entry of 'Deposit Account' for the Fin
            Account Type field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Keep the default entry of 'Active' for the status
            field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter a description (eg ABC Customer Prepaid Account) for
            the 'Fin Account Name' field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the Fin Account Pin field blank<note>
                <para>CHECK: I think this is only used in creation of Gift
                Cards and Certificates..)</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the Fin Account Code field blank<note>
                <para>CHECK: I think this is only used in the creation of Gift
                Cards and Certificates...</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The currency field will be the default currency of Company
            (eg USD). If this account is to be in another currency (eg EUR)
            then select it from the drop down list.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Set the Organization Party ID field to be 'Company'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Fill in the Owner Party Id field with the party id of the
            customer who has the Financial Account (eg DemoCustomer or
            DemoCustCompany)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Fill in the 'Post to Gl Account field' to post the
            transactions for this financial account to post to a specific GL
            Account</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Select the current date from the calendar to fill in the
            'From date' field<note>
                <para>It can be left blank and still appears to work</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Thru date' field blank <note>
                <para>CHECK: I think this could be used to close or stop the
                use of an account ..</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the default of 'Is Refundable' as 'Y' <note>
                <para>CHECK: I think this will allow money to be refunded to
                this account - eg if you have a return or credit for the
                customer</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Replenish Payment ID' blank<note>
                <para>CHECK: Not sure what this is - maybe to automatically
                replenish account if it gets to a certain limit???)Leave the
                'Replenish Level' blank (NOTE TO CHECK: Not sure what this is
                but probably linked to Replenish Payment ID where you set the
                limit - eg $100)</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>Press the 'Create' button and message appears saying that the
        account was successfully created</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update an existing Financial Account?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Search' button on the Financial Account main
            screen</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>A list of all existing Financial Accounts will be
            displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Create/Update Financial' screen is displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Update the details of the financial account</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Update' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Find Financial Accounts</title>

      <para>This screen is used to locate existing financial accounts that
      have been created.</para>

      <para>It also includes the option to use the 'Advanced Search' button to
      display additional fields that can be used to locate a specific
      financial account.</para>

      <para>New Financial Accounts can be created using the 'Create New
      Financial Account' button.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do locate an existing Financial Account?</title>

        <para>Press the 'Search' button</para>

        <para>A list of all existing Financial Accounts will be
        displayed.</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I delete an existing Financial Account?</title>

        <para>Press the 'Search' button on the Financial Account main
        screen</para>

        <para>A list of all existing Financial Accounts will be
        displayed</para>

        <para>Press the 'Delete' button next to the Financial Account that
        needs to be deleted.</para>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Help protlet List Bank Account</title>

      <para>The default display is a list of financial accounts that have the
      type 'bank account'. A company will have at least one main bank account
      that will be used to accept payments from customers or to generate
      payments to suppliers. The financial account will mirror the
      transactions appearing on a bank statement so that they can be
      reconciled with the true bank statement when it arrives.</para>

      <para>Click on the bank account to display further information.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I remove a bank account?</title>

        <para>Press the 'Delete' button next to the account that needs to be
        deleted.</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I remove a bank account?</title>

        <para>Press the 'Delete' button next to the account that needs to be
        deleted.</para>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="accounting_FindTaxAuthority">
    <title>Tax Authorities</title>

    <para>A tax authority is legal body usually the state (country) that
    imposes a financial levy on business transactions.</para>

    <para>In OFBiz tax authorities are used to calculate where business or
    related taxes are due.</para>

    <para>Tax setup is very important as it links into the calculated price
    that you can charge your customers and also flows through into any related
    legal documents that are generated (eg Sales Order, Sales Invoice,
    Purchase Order etc).</para>

    <para>Each country or region will have specific rules regarding what
    should or should not be taxed. There will also be very strict regulations
    on how taxable transactions should be recorded and tracked in the general
    ledger or chart of accounts.</para>

    <para>Tax authority setup allows configuration of the following :</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Income tax</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Value Added Tax (VAT) / Goods and Services Tax (GST)</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Import / Export tax /Custom and Excise Duty</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>State, City or County taxes</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="accounting_FindAgreement">
    <title>Agreements</title>

    <sect1>
      <title>Aggreements</title>

      <para>An agreement is a way of recording a business arrangements or
      contract that your business makes with other companies or individuals.
      Common examples include Payment Terms (where you allow a customer up to
      30 days to pay you) or Prompt Payment Discounts (where you offer a
      reduction on the amount owing if your customer pays you before a certain
      date)</para>

      <para>It can be used for the following:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Defining Payment Terms for Customers or Suppliers</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Defining Sales Commissions</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Setting up Prompt Payment Discounts</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Setting up Price Lists (NOTE TO DO: Need to investigate how
          this logic overlaps with PRICE RULES in Catalog Manager)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Defining Late Fee Penalties</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Defining preferred freight carriers or specific codes to be
          used</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Edit Agreements Roles</title>

      <para>This screen is used to assign a party roles for an
      agreement.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I add a party role to an agreement?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Use the lookup to select the 'Party Id'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Use the drop down box to select the 'Party Role Id'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Add' button (NOTE: If the party does not have
            this role associated with them then an error will be
            displayed)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The new entry will be displayed in the lower part of the
            screen</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update a party role for an agreement?</title>

        <para>Party roles can only be added and deleted. They cannot be
        updated.</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I delete a party role from an agreement?</title>

        <para>Press the 'Remove' button for the entry that needs to be
        deleted.</para>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Agreement Work Effort</title>

      <para>This screen is used to link a work effort to the whole agreement
      or an individual agreement item.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I add a work effort to an agreement?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Use the drop down box to select the 'Agreement Item Seq
            Id'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Use the lookup to select the 'Workeffort Id'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Add' button</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The new entry is displayed in the lower part of the
            screen</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update a work effort for an agreement?</title>

        <para>Work efforts can only be added or deleted. They cannot be
        updated</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I delete a work effort from an agreement?</title>

        <para>Press the 'Delete' button for the entry that needs to be
        deleted</para>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Agreement Items</title>

      <para>This section describes the screens that manage different agreement
      items.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>Edit Agreement Geo</title>

        <para>This screen is used to create a geographical location for an
        agreement item.<note>
            <para>A new entry can be created or removed but not
            updated.</para>
          </note></para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Edit Agreement Item Party</title>

        <para>This screen is used to add or update a party linked to an
        agreement item. This could be useful for storing specific contact
        names associated with an agreement item.</para>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I update a party for an agreement item?</title>

          <para>Parties for an agreement item cannot be updated. They can only
          be added or removed.</para>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Edit Agreement Item Product</title>

        <para>This screen is used to create or update a product entry for an
        agreement item.</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Edit Agreement Item Supplier Product</title>

        <para>This screen is used to create or update a product entry for a
        supplier agreement item. Any updates made in this screen can also be
        viewed in Catalog Manager for the product under the product
        'Suppliers' and 'Agreements' tabs.</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Edit Agreement Item</title>

        <para>This screen allows specific items to be added to agreement.
        Currently these are limited to the following:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Pricing</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Commission Rate</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Sub-Agreement</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Exhibit</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Section</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I create an agreement item?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Create Agreement Item' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Edit Agreement Item' screen is displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select the 'Agreement Item Type Id' from the drop down
              box</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Use the drop down box to select the 'Currency' for the
              Agreement Item</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter any 'Agreement Text' if required</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter path for 'Agreement Image' if required</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>A new sub menu will be displayed containing
              'Promotions','Terms','Products','Party' and 'Geo' for additional
              details that can be setup for the agreement item</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I edit an agreement item?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select the agreement item to be updated by clicking on the
              Agreement Item Id</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Edit Agreement Item' screen is displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Update the fields required (NOTE: Additional details can
              be updated by selecting the Promotions, Terms, Product, Party or
              Geo sub menus)</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Edit Agreement Item Term</title>

        <para>This screen is used to create or update the terms for an
        agreement item.</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>List Agreement Geo</title>

        <para>This screen is used to display a list of the geographical
        locations that are valid for the agreement item.</para>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I create a new geographical location for an agreement
          item?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'New' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Edit Agreement Geographical Application' screen is
              displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Use the drop down box to select the 'Geo Id'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I delete a geographical location for an agreement
          item?</title>

          <para>Press the 'Delete' button for the entry that needs to be
          deleted</para>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Agreement Items Parties</title>

        <para>This screen is used to display any parties that have been linked
        to this agreement item.</para>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I create a party for an agreement item?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'New' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Edit Agreement Item Party' screen is displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Manually enter or use the lookup to select the 'Party
              Id'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I remove a party for an agreement item?</title>

          <para>Press the 'Delete' button for the entry that needs to be
          deleted.</para>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Agreement Item Products</title>

        <para>This screen is used to link a specific product or products to an
        agreement. This can be useful for restricting a discount or product
        pricing to a particular product (or range of products) for a specific
        customer.</para>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I add a product to an agreement item?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'New Product' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Edit Agreement Item Product' screen is
              displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Manually enter or use the lookup to select the 'Product
              Id'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the 'Price' to be associated to the product for this
              agreement item</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I update a product linked to an agreement
          item?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select the product required by clicking on the 'Product
              Id'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Edit Agreement Item Product' screen is
              displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Update the 'Price' for the product (NOTE: Only product
              price is available for update)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I delete a product from an agreement item?</title>

          <para>Press the 'Remove' button on the entry that needs to be
          deleted</para>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>List Agreement Item Supplier Products</title>

        <para>This screen is used to link a specific product (or range of
        products) to an agreement. This can be useful for restricting a
        discount or product pricing to a product (or range of products) for a
        particular supplier.</para>

        <note>
          <para>Products created here will be linked to the product and can be
          view using Catalog Manager. Entries can be viewed under the Product
          'Suppliers' and 'Agreements' tabs.</para>
        </note>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I add a product to an agreement item?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'New Product' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Edit Agreement Item Product' screen is
              displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Manually enter or use the lookup to select the 'Product
              Id'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the 'Available From Date'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Leave the 'Thru Date' blank</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Using the drop down box select the 'Supplier Order Pref
              Id'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the 'Last Price'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter 'Supplier Product Id'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter any other details as required or leave blank</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I update a product linked to an agreement
          item?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select the product required by clicking on the 'Product
              Id'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Edit Agreement Item Product' screen is
              displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Update the details as required</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I delete a product from an agreement item?</title>

          <para>Press the 'Remove' button on the entry that needs to be
          deleted</para>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Agreements Item Terms</title>

        <para>This screen is used to enter or maintain terms that are specific
        to an agreement item. The terms available are the same as those found
        under the 'Agreement Terms' tab and any related terms will be
        displayed both here and under the 'Agreement Items' tab .</para>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I create a term for an agreement item?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Create Term' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Edit Agreement Item Term' screen is displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the term details required</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I update a term for an agreement item?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select the term for the agreement item by clicking on the
              term id</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Edit Agreement Item Term' screen is displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Update the details required</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I delete a term for an agreement item?</title>

          <para>Press the 'Remove' button on the term entry that needs to be
          deleted.</para>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>List Agreement Items</title>

        <para>This screen is used to display a list of items that have been
        created for an agreement.</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Agreements Item Promotions</title>

        <para>This screen is used to enter or maintain any promotions that are
        associated with the Agreement Item. This can be useful if you want to
        limit where a particular promotion is applied. Promotions are setup in
        Catalog Manager and can be selected here.</para>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I add a promotion to an agreement item?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Add New Promotion' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Edit Agreement Promo Applications' screen is
              displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select the 'Product Promo Id' from the drop down
              box</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the 'From Date'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the 'Thru Date' if required (NOTE:This can be left
              blank)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the 'Sequence Num' if required</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I edit an existing promotion for an agreement
          item?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select the agreement item promotion by clicking on on the
              promotion id</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Edit Agreement Promo Applications' screen is
              displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Update the details required</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I delete a promotion from an agreement item?</title>

          <para>Press the 'Remove' button on the entry that needs to be
          deleted.</para>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Edit Agreement Terms</title>

      <para>Agreement Terms are the rules that make up the agreement.
      Agreements may have a one or more terms.</para>

      <para>Examples of agreement terms from a sales and purchase viewpoint
      include the following:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Payment due within a certain timeframe (eg 30 days)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Discounts for early payment</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Specifying Late fee penalties</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Purchasing agreements</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Exclusive Relationship</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist><note>
          <para>Agreements can also be specified for Employment, Legal, Non
          Compete etc.</para>
        </note></para>

      <para>Agreement terms are configured by linking them to the Invoice Item
      Type.</para>

      <note>
        <para>The drop down box for 'Invoice Item Type' contains what appears
        to be duplicates for items such as 'Invoice Fee', 'Invoice Discount',
        'Invoice Finished Good Item' etc. These are NOT duplicates one of
        these entries refers to the Sales Invoice and the other refers to the
        Purchase Invoice. As the descriptions are exactly the same it is
        impossible to know which refers to which so needs to be done using
        trial and error</para>
      </note>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I add a payment term for 30 days?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select 'Payment Net Days' from the 'Term Type Id' drop down
            box</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter '30' in the 'Term Days' field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>ress the 'Submit' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I add a discount term of 2% if paid within 10
        days?</title>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select 'Payment Discounted if paid with Specified Days' from
            the 'Term Type Id' drop down box</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter '2' in the 'Term Value' field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter '10' in the 'Term Days' field</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I specify pricing in a specific currency only for this
        customer or supplier?</title>

        <para>This is done using the 'Agreement Items' sub menu</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I delete a payment term?</title>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Locate the payment term required</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Remove'on the entry that needs to be
            removed</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Edit Agreement</title>

      <para>The 'Agreement' sub menu is used to enter the basic details
      required for setting up a new agreement or editing an existing
      one.</para>

      <para>It can be used to create or update the following details for an
      Agreement:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>The parties the agreement is between and their roles</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The agreement type (eg Sales, Purchase, Commission, Employment
          etc)</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Specific products</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Start and End Date</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Description</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I edit an agreement?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Find the agreement that needs to be amended</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Click on Agreement Id</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Edit Agreement' screen will be displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Amend the details required and press the 'Submit' button
            (NOTE: Additional agreement details can be updated via the other
            tabs eg Agreement Terms, Agreement Roles, Agreement Items and
            Agreement Work Effort Appls)</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I copy an existing agreement?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Find the agreement that needs to be copied</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Click on the Agreement Id</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Edit Agreement' screen will be displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>At the bottom of the screen press the 'Copy' in the 'Copy
            Agreement' window (NOTE: The default tick boxes will copy the
            agreement terms, products and party. If not required then click on
            the boxes to stop them being copied)</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Find Agreements</title>

      <para>The default screen is for the Agreements tab is 'Find Agreements'.
      It is used to locate existing agreements that have been created. The
      user has the option to:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>use the 'Find' button to locate an existing agreement
          or</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>create a new one by clicking on the 'Create Agreement'
          button.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I locate an existing agreement?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Enter search option details if known</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Find' button</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>A list of existing agreements will be displayed</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I create a new agreement?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Create Agreement' button</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Edit Agreement' screen is displayed</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the details required and press the 'Submit'
            button</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I cancel an agreement?</title>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Locate the agreement required</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Press the 'Cancel' button on the agreement entry that needs
            to be cancelled</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="accounting_ListFixedAssets">
    <title>Fixed Assets</title>

    <para/>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="accounting_FindGlobalGlAccount">
    <title>Global GL Settings</title>

    <para>The Global GL Settings tab is where a limited global or 'master'
    accounting configuration can be done. These include:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Reviewing the chart of account structure or hierarchy (Navigate
        Accounts)</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Adding new accounts</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Updating an existing account (eg. change the description, change
        the type of account, change the parent account or hierarchy)</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Linking an account from the master chart to 'Company' or any
        other of your company departments, subsidiaries or business
        units</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Creating new component costs for products</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Setting default accounts for different types of payments</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Setting default accounts for invoice line items</para>

        <note>
          <para>This includes all types eg: payroll, commission, purchase,
          return, sales etc</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <note>
      <para>Some of the configuration specified here can be over-ridden using
      the 'Organization GL Settings' tab</para>
    </note>

    <sect1>
      <title>Cost Centers</title>

      <para/>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Find GL Account Category</title>

      <para/>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>View Foreign Exchange Rates</title>

      <para>Foreign exchange rates are used to convert from one currency to
      another. Usually a business will want to work in one main currency (eg
      GBP) but will allow transactions in other currencies (eg EUR, USD).
      These currencies will need to be converted to the main currency at some
      point in order to generate financial reports (eg Balance Sheet or Income
      Statement) and most importantly to adhere to tax authority
      regulations.</para>

      <para>OFBiz currently allows you to input to 3 different rates for the
      same currency using the 'Purpose' field. With this you can specify
      whether the conversion is to be used internally, externally or leave the
      field blank. Also the start and end date for a conversion can be
      specified beforehand.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I add a new foreign exchange rate?</title>

        <para>To add a new rate for US Dollars (USD) to Euro (EUR)</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Using the drop down box on the 'From Currency' field, select
            'American Dollar - USD'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Using the drop down box on the 'To Currency' field, select
            'Euro - EUR'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Purpose' field can be left blank or you can select
            'Internal Conversion' or 'External Conversion' from the drop down
            list</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the exchange rate in the 'Rate' field (eg
            0.72883)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter the 'From Date' (NOTE: If left blank then will default
            to the current date and time)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Leave the 'Thru Date' blank</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Click the 'Update Foreign Currency Rates' button</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The new foreign exchange rate will be displayed</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I update an existing foreign exchange rate?</title>

        <para>Existing foreign exchange rates cannot be updated - instead the
        existing rate is expired and a new rate is created. Currently up to 3
        different exchange rates can be created by using the 'Purpose' field
        to distinguish them.</para>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I delete a foreign exchange rate?</title>

        <para>Foreign exchange rates cannot be deleted. Existing rates can be
        expired by entering a new exchange rate for the same currency and
        purpose.</para>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>View Rates</title>

      <para/>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Edit Invoice Item Type</title>

      <para/>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Edit Payment Method Type</title>

      <para/>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Edit Cost Calculations</title>

      <para/>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Edit Custom Time Period</title>

      <para/>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Find Global GL Account</title>

      <para>The default screen is for the Global GL Settings tab is 'List
      Accounts'. If the demo data has been loaded then the default screen
      displays a list of the general ledger accounts that form the Global
      Chart of Accounts template. All general ledger accounts must exist in
      the global template before it can be assinged to be used at the
      organisation level (eg Company) It is used to view or edit the details
      of the general ledger accounts in the global template and there are
      options to print or export the account details.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>How do I view details for an account?</title>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Locate the account required</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Click on account id</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The account details will be displayed</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>

  <chapter xml:id="accounting_ListCompanies">
    <title>Organization GL Settings</title>

    <para><emphasis role="bold">Available Internal
    Organizations</emphasis></para>

    <para>The default screen shows a list of Party Groups that have the role
    of 'Internal Organization' associated with them. If you have installed the
    demo data then the default company 'Company' as well as departments /
    business units and regional subsidiaries will be displayed.</para>

    <para>The list has two command buttons, Setup and Accounting.</para>

    <sect1>
      <title>Setup</title>

      <para>In the Demo data the default Company is set up. To setup other
      organizations:<orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>In the Available Internal Organizations list clicke the
            'Setup' button</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The Accounting Preferences screen is displayed with defaults
            copied from the Company record.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Enter any changes that are required (eg Invoice Prefix,
            Error Journal name - as you may want error transactions from
            separate departments to be handled differently...)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Click Add</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist></para>

      <para>The Setup menu includes options to manage:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Accounting Preferences</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Chart of Accounts</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Journals</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>GL Account Defaults</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Time Period</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist> The following sections discuss each of these
      features.</para>

      <sect2>
        <title>Accounting Preferences</title>

        <para>Accounting Preferences are a set of configuration details that
        are related to a party. To appear on this screen the party must be
        setup with the role of 'Internal Organisation'. This means that you
        can add the internal organisation role to a party and they will be
        added to this screen and then can be configured.</para>

        <para>The master default party is 'Company' but preferences can also
        be setup for internal departments as described in the section above.
        Unless overridden then then all other parties appearing on this screen
        will take their default setup from 'Company' <note>
            <para>The majority of the configuration information displayed in
            Accounting Preferences are taken from the Enumeration
            entity.</para>
          </note></para>

        <para>It is used for setting specifying information related to the
        accounting setup for a specific organisation or parties that exist
        within an organisation such as business units, cost centres,
        departments ,subsidiaries etc. Information that can be setup include
        the following:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The start date of the Time Periods and Fiscal or Accounting
            Year (eg 1st April, 1st January, 1st June etc)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Tax Return Form<note>
                <para>Need to check how important this is and where it is
                used.......possibly some kind of reporting???</para>
              </note></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The method to be used for calculating Cost of Goods Sold
            (COGS)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Base Currency - eg USD, GBP, EUR etc (NOTE: May have main
            company in USD but a subsidiary in EUR etc)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Invoice prefix, numbering and sequencing (eg you may want
            each business unit / subsidiary to have its own invoice numbering
            or sequence etc)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Quote prefix, number and sequencing</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Method to be used for refunds (eg cheque, direct bank
            credit, voucher credit etc...)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Specify which journal will be used to store error
            transactions</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <note>
          <para>Key things that are usually need to be amended include the
          base currency for the company, fiscal year information and invoice
          numbering prefix or sequencing.</para>
        </note>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>About GL Account Defaults</title>

        <para>The GL Account Defaults screens are are method to setup rules
        that are used to translate business transactions into accounting
        transactions. It currently is made up of 12 sub menus that can be used
        to map various transaction type codes to a specific general ledger
        account Accounting transactions are made up of a Debit Entry and a
        Credit Entry. The GL Account defaults screens help map which accounts
        are to be used to generate a each part of the transaction. This means
        that certain mappings will be used to generate the Debit (or DR) entry
        part of the transaction and others used to generate the Credit (or CR)
        entry part of the transaction. <note>
            <para>Many of the accounting transactions are generated
            'automatically' (or in the background) using the the accounting
            services SECAS / EECAS.</para>
          </note></para>

        <para>The GL Account Type is used to specify the default account that
        certain transactions (eg Accounts Payable, Accounts Receivable, etc)
        are posted to. An accounting transaction (or journal entry) is made up
        of two parts - a Debit Entry and a Credit Entry that balance each
        other. The GL Account Type is used to translate one side of the
        journal entry.</para>

        <para>GL Account Types are stored in Entity GLAccountType which can be
        viewed via Entity Data Maintenance in the Webtools menu. There are
        currently 57 different GL Account Types that are part of the OFBiz
        demo data but only 19 of these are setup as mappings How the GL
        Account Type is used is best shown by an example. A very simple
        description of an online Sales Order Process could be as
        follows:</para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Customer Orders a Product (and Creates a Sales Order)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Customer Pays for Product (via Credit Card, Internet Banking
            etc)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Vendor confirms Payment and Dispatches the Product to the
            Customer</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>Let's focus on the first part step of 3 in more detail.</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>The vendor has checked their bank statement and seen that
            the customer has paid</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>In OFBiz Order Manager they will then look up the relevant
            Sales Order and then click the 'Receive Payment' button to log the
            payment in the system</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The 'Receive Payment' button is a trigger for an 'automatic'
            accounting transaction</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The transaction type that is triggered is called 'Incoming
            Payment'</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>The accounting entries generated are: DR 112000 Undeposited
            Funds , CR 120000 Accounts Receivable</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>The CR (or Credit) entry for the transaction is created by the
        GL Acccount Type mapping for 'Accounts Receivable' (which by using the
        demo data default will go the 120000 Accounts Receivable)</para>

        <para>The DR (or Debit) entry for the transaction is created by a
        different GL Account default, the Payment Method Id / GL Account Id
        mapping (eg Cash is setup as 112000 Undeposited Receipts)</para>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I create a new GL Account Type default
          mapping?</title>

          <para>There are currently 57 different GL Account Types that come as
          part of the demo data with OFBiz. This should be enough to manage
          the vast majority of business transactions. These instructions show
          how to add a mapping using the default data</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select the 'GL Account Type Id' from the drop down
              list</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select the 'GL Account' to map it to from the drop down
              list</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Save' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The new GL Account Type mapping is displayed in the list
              at the bottom of the screen</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>

          <note>
            <para>If none of the demo data GL Account Types are sufficient
            then new ones can be added using Entity Data Maintenance and the
            entity 'GLAccountType' in the Webtools menu.</para>
          </note>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I update a GL Account Type default mapping?</title>

          <para>A GL Account Type mapping cannot be updated directly but needs
          to be removed then re-created. If you try to update an existing
          entry you will get an 'duplicate key' error message.</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the entry that you want
              to update</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The entry is removed from the list of entries
              displayed</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select the 'GL Account Type Id' from the drop down
              list</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select the updated 'GL Account' to map it to from the drop
              down list</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Save' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The new GL Account mapping is displayed in the list at the
              bottom of the screen</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I delete a GL Account Type default mapping?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the entry that you want
              to delete</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The entry is removed from the list of entries
              displayed</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Gl Account Default Screens</title>

        <para>There are thirteen sub-screens underGL Account Defaults. They
        are discussed in the following sections.</para>

        <sect3>
          <title>Party GL Accounts</title>

          <para>The Party / GL Account mapping allows the translation of
          different account types (eg Accounts Receivable, Accounts Payable
          etc) for a party to be mapped to a separate general ledger account.
          The party role (eg Bill To Customer) is also used to define the
          mapping even further. OFBiz demo data setup comes with no entries
          here. It is used as a way of implementing subledger functionality in
          OFBiz. Subledger functionality is where a higher level account can
          be split into lower levels. In this case these lower levels can be
          by party.</para>

          <para>An example could be that a business may want to use the
          general ledger to track the Accounts Receivable (AR) by customer so
          the chart of account would be setup something like as follows:
          120000 Accounts Receivable</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>120010 Accounts Receivable - Customer A</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>120020 Accounts Receiviable - Customer B</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>120030 Accounts Receivalbe - Customer C</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>This has the main AR account is at the top of the hierarchy
          and 3 sub accounts below it. Entries for Customers A, B and C would
          be setup with a role of 'Bill From Customer' as this is a role
          associated with the customer when the Sales Invoice is
          generated.When a transaction matching the criteria is processed in
          the system then these mappings will control where it is posted to.In
          the case of Customer A any AR transactions with role 'Bill To
          Customer' are posted to '120010' instead of the standard
          '120000</para>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I add a new Party / GL Account mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Enter or Lookup the party for the 'Party Id'
                field</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'Role Type Id' from the drop down list<note>
                    <para>Be careful that you select the correct role for the
                    transactions you want to track......)</para>
                  </note></para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'GL Account Type Id' from the drop down
                list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'GL Account Id' from the drop down
                list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Add' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The new entry will be displayed at the bottom of the
                screen</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I update a Party / GL Account mapping?</title>

            <para>Only the GL Account Id linked to the mapping can be
            updated.</para>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Locate the Party / GL Account entry that needs to be
                updated</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the new 'GL Account Id' from the drop down list
                next to the entry</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Update' button next to the entry</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I remove a Party / GL Account mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Locate the Party / GL Account entry that needs to be
                removed</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Delete' button next to the entry</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>Tax Authority GL Accounts</title>

          <para>The Tax Authority / GL Account default is used to map
          different tax authorities to different general ledger accounts. This
          setup will affect one side of a journal entry only. <note>
              <para>A tax authority is legal body usually the state (country)
              that imposes a financial levy on business transactions.</para>
            </note></para>

          <para>Normal business rules require you will to keep track amounts
          collected or paid to different tax authorities separately. This
          mapping ensures that money collected or paid to various tax
          authorities (eg through Sales Orders, Purchase Orders etc) can be
          separated into specific accounts</para>

          <para>The OFBiz demo data comes with 9 entries to show an example of
          how this can be setup using the some of the US states as separate
          tax authorities.</para>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I add a Tax Authority / GL Account mapping?</title>

            <para>Unlike the other GL Account defaults you cannot add a Tax
            Authority / GL mapping through these screens. It needs to be done
            via the 'GL Accounts' sub menu under the 'Tax Authorities' menu.
            The method of how to add a mapping using the 'Tax Authorities' is
            shown below.</para>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>From the Accounting Manager / Tax Authorities Menu press
                the 'Edit' button next to the Tax Authority required</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the sub menu 'GL Accounts'</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Enter or Lookup the party for the 'Organisation Party
                Id' field (NOTE: Use 'Company' as default)</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Enter or Lookup the GL Account to be mapped to</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Add' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The mapping will be displayed at the bottom of the
                screen.</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Return to the Tax Authority / GL Account default and
                this new mapping will be shown in the list</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I update a Tax Authority / GL Account
            mapping?</title>

            <para>Only the GL Account Id linked to the mapping can be
            updated.</para>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Locate the Tax Authority / GL Account entry that needs
                to be updated</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the new 'GL Account Id' from the drop down list
                next to the entry</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Update' button next to the entry</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I remove a Tax Authority / GL Account
            mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Locate the Tax Authority / GL Account entry that needs
                to be removed</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Delete' button next to the entry</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>Credit Card Type GL Accounts</title>

          <para>The Credit Card Type / GL Account default is used to map
          different types of credit card to different general ledger accounts.
          <note>
              <para>This setup will affect one side of a journal entry
              only.</para>
            </note></para>

          <para>This type of mapping is useful if you need to track the
          amounts to be collected from different credit card agents. The OFBiz
          demo data comes with some setup here<note>
              <para>The demo entries appear to be duplicated...has something
              changed in ENUM for defining each credit card
              type.....?????</para>
            </note></para>

          <para>Examples are as follows:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>American Express</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Visa</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Mastercard</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Diners Club</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I add a Credit Card Type GL Account mapping?</title>

            <para>There are 10 mappings that come as part of the OFBiz demo
            data but they do appear to be duplicated for some reason.</para>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'Card Type' from the drop down list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the updated 'GL Account Id' to map it to from the
                drop down list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Add' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The updated 'Credit Card Type / GL Account' mapping is
                displayed in the list at the bottom of the screen <note>
                    <para>Used 'Visa' as an example to update and the
                    'CCT_VISA' was updated but the 'Visa' one wasnt. This is
                    probably related to the duplication.</para>
                  </note></para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I update a Credit Card Type GL Account
            mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'Card Type' from the drop down list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the updated 'GL Account Id' to map it to from the
                drop down lis</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Add' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The updated 'Credit Card Type / GL Account' mapping is
                displayed in the list at the bottom of the screen</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>

            <note>
              <para>Used 'Visa' as an example to update and the 'CCT_VISA' was
              updated but the 'Visa' one wasnt. This is probably related to
              the duplication.</para>
            </note>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I remove a Credit Card Type GL Account
            mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the entry that you
                want to delete</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The entry is removed from the list of entries
                displayed</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>Variance Reason GL Accounts</title>

          <para>The Variance Reason / GL Account default is used for mapping
          any stock differences to a particular general ledger account. If
          there are variances in the number of products that are in stock then
          this affects the value of inventory in the general ledger. By using
          this GL default you can offset any differences in stock to the
          relevant general ledger account.</para>

          <para>The number of products (or items) in stock can vary. These
          differences can be caused by numerous reasons. Some of these could
          be as follows:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Products have been damaged</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Products were lost or stolen</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Products were found</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Under or over supply of a Product from a Supplier (eg. You
              have ordered 10 and 11 are delivered....)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Free samples or giveaways to potential clients <note>
                  <para>These mappings are used in Catalog Manager when a
                  manual inventory adjustment is done through the Inventory
                  Item screens.</para>
                </note></para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I add a new Variance Reason / GL Account
            mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'Variance Reason Id' from the drop down
                list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'GL Account Type Id' to map it to from the
                drop down list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Add' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The new 'Variance Reason / GL Account Type' mapping is
                displayed in the list at the bottom of the screen</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I update a Variance Reason / GL Account
            mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'Variance Reason Id' from the drop down
                list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the updated 'GL Account Type Id' to map it to
                from the drop down list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Add' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The updated 'Variance Reason / GL Account Type' mapping
                is displayed in the list at the bottom of the screen</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I remove a Variance Reason / GL Account
            mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the entry that you
                want to delete</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The entry is removed from the list of entries
                displayed</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>Payment Method GL Account</title>

          <para>The Payment Method GL Account Type Id is used to map the
          different payment methods (eg Cash, Cheque etc) to a specific GL
          Account Type Id. This will translate to one side of a GL entry
          only.</para>

          <para>A Payment Method is just a way to define the ways in which
          payments can be made. Each payment method can be linked to a
          different account in the general ledger. A main GL account used
          would be the one that represents the Company bank account. In the
          demo data mappings Electronic Funds Transfer, Company Account,
          Financial Account are all linked to the Company bank account GL
          account.</para>

          <para>OFBiz demo data defines 15 different payment methods as
          follows:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Cash</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Certified Cheque</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Company Account</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Company Cheque</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Electronic Funds Transfer<note>
                  <para>CHECK: Problem with definition or terminology - is
                  this a Direct Debit.... ?? A direct debit is controlled by
                  the payee and an automatic payment via bank account is
                  controlled by the payer)</para>
                </note></para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Billing Account</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Cash on Delivery (COD)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>eBay</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Offline Payment<note>
                  <para>Is this ambiguous - since COD is an offline
                  payment...</para>
                </note></para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>PayPal</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>WorldPay</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Financial Account</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Gift Certificate</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Money Order</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Personal Cheque</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <note>
            <para>A point to note is that these payment methods don't include
            Credit Cards....(which I think is on purpose...). The majority of
            these payment methods are linked to 'Undeposited Receipts' but an
            additional accounting transaction may be needed once the funds
            have cleared and are available in the Company bank account.</para>
          </note>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I add a new Payment Method Id / GL Account Id
            mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'Payment Method Type' from the drop down
                list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'GL Account Id' to map it to from the drop
                down list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Save' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The new Payment Method Type / GL Account Type mapping is
                displayed in the list at the bottom of the screen</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I update a Payment Method Id / GL Account Id
            mapping?</title>

            <para>A Payment Method Type / GL Account Type mapping cannot be
            updated directly but needs to be removed then re-created. If you
            try to update an existing entry you will get an 'duplicate key'
            error message</para>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the entry that you
                want to update</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The entry is removed from the list of entries
                displayed</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'Payment Method Type' from the drop down
                list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the updated 'GL Account Type' to map it to from
                the drop down list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Save' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The new Payment Method Type / GL Account Type mapping is
                displayed in the list at the bottom of the screen</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I remove a Payment Method Id / Gl Account Id
            mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the entry that you
                want to delete</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The entry is removed from the list of entries
                displayed</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>Payment Type GL Account</title>

          <para>The Payment Type GL Account Type Id is used to translate (or
          map) the different payment types to a specific GL Account Type Id.
          The GL Account Type Id is then used via the 'GL Account Type Id'
          defaults to translate to one side of a journal entry. <note>
              <para>This GL Account default is used to link to another one of
              the GL Account defaults. A Payment Type is just a way to
              categorize transactions.</para>
            </note></para>

          <para>Examples of Payment Types could be as follows:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Commission Payments</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Customer Payments</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Vendor (or Supplier) Payments</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Customer Refunds</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Customer Prepayments or Deposits</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>These payment types can then be mapped to the required account
          type in the Chart of Account. Examples of these type of mappings
          could be as follows:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Customer Payments are mapped to Account Receivable</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Vendor (or Supplier) Payment are mapped to Account
              Payable</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Customer Refunds are mapped to Customer Credits</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I add a Payment Type / GL Account Type Id
            mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'Payment Type Id' from the drop down
                list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'GL Account Type Id' to map it to from the
                drop down list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Save' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The new 'Payment Type / GL Account Type' mapping is
                displayed in the list at the bottom of the screen</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I update a Payment Type / GL Account Type Id
            mapping?</title>

            <para>A Payment Type / GL Account Type mapping cannot be updated
            directly but needs to be removed then re-created. If you try to
            update an existing entry you will get an 'duplicate key' error
            message.</para>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the entry that you
                want to update</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The entry is removed from the list of entries
                displayed</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'Payment Type Id' from the drop down
                list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the updated 'GL Account Type Id' to map it to
                from the drop down list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Save' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The new 'Payment Type / GL Account Type' mapping is
                displayed in the list at the bottom of the screen</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I remove a Payment Type / GL Account Type Id
            mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the entry that you
                want to delete</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The entry is removed from the list of entries
                displayed</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>Purchase Invoice</title>

          <para>The Purchase Invoice sub menu is used to specify the default
          account to be used for the individual line items that appear on a
          Purchase Invoice. The items are identified by a line description
          which can be mapped to a specific general ledger account. Purchase
          invoices can be made up of a variety of items as well as the product
          that is being bought (eg discounts, promotions, work effort or
          labour costs etc). The majority of businesses will want to track
          these type of items separately in the general ledger and this screen
          will allow this type of setup. This setup will translate to one side
          of the journal entry only. <important>
              <para>This screen is one of the screens where the default
              entries that are displayed here are entered via the Global GL
              Settings under the sub menu 'Invoice Item Type'. This screen
              allows users to override the global settings for the Purchase
              Invoice item type. An example of why this could be necessary
              could be that a company many want to isolate the sales reporting
              of a specific department or business unit separately (eg
              subledgers etc) but still have the option of a 'catch all'
              global general ledger account.</para>

              <para>Need to do more investigation but the it looks like these
              Purchase Invoice mappings dont work when used as part of the
              Purchase Order to Purchase Invoice Process.(Have been doing some
              tests to try and get it to post to a different account than
              'Uninvoiced Shipment Receipts' and 'Inventory' but hasnt worked
              so far.) We need to be able to specify things such as Sales Tax,
              Freight and any Purchase Order adjustments. These override
              mappings do work if there is no Purchase Order just a Purchase
              Invoice as shown in the simple process below.</para>
            </important></para>

          <para>How the Purchase Invoice mappings are used is best shown by an
          example. A very simple description of a Purchase Invoice Process
          could be as follows:</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>You have ordered something from a supplier (eg indirect
              purchasing such as stationery etc via phone)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The Supplier ships the products to you<note>
                  <para>as they are not stored in the Warehouse but in your
                  offices - so dont need an Inventory Receive.....????</para>
                </note></para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>You receive the product and an invoice from the Supplier
              (Purchase Invoice)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>You enter the Purchase Invoice pay the Supplier the amount
              invoiced</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>

          <para>Let's focus on step of 4 in more detail.</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>You have received the product from the supplier with an
              invoice</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>In OFBiz you enter the Purchase Invoice using 'Create New'
              in the 'Invoices' menu of Accounting Manager</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Using the 'Items' sub menu you can create individual items
              on the Purchase Invoice (eg Paper, Pens, Sales Tax etc and they
              dont need to have a Product Id associated with them)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>When you add a new invoice item to the Purchase Invoice it
              is the 'Invoice Item Type' that is affected by the Purchase
              Invoice override mappings</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The Purchase Invoice can then be moved to various statuses
              (Approved, Received, Ready or Cancelled)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>When the status is moved to 'Ready' this is a trigger for
              an 'automatic' accounting transaction</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The transaction type generated is called 'Purchase
              Invoice' and it uses the Purchase Invoice override
              mappings</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>Transaction Type: Purchase Invoice, DR 516100 Purchase Order
          Adjustments , DR ????? Sales Tax, CR 210000 Accounts Payable</para>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I add a new Purchase Invoice override
            mapping?</title>

            <para>By default there are no Purchase Invoice override mappings
            that are configured as part of the OFBiz demo data.</para>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'Invoice Purchase Item Type' from the drop
                down list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the ' Invoice Override Expense GL Account Id' to
                map it to from the drop down list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Save' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The new mapping will be displayed in the 'Invoice
                Override Expense GL Account' column in the list at the bottom
                of the screen</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I update a Purchase Invoice override
            mapping?</title>

            <para>An existing Purchase Invoice override mapping cannot be
            updated but needs to be removed and a new mapping added. If you
            try to add an override to an item that already has an override you
            will get a duplicate record error message.</para>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I remove a Purchase Invoice override
            mapping?</title>

            <note>
              <para>Only the override mapping can be deleted. The default
              mapping record cannot be deleted here (even though the Remove
              button is displayed next to it!)</para>
            </note>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Locate the entry that needs the override deleted in the
                list of Purchase Invoice override mappings</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the entry</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The override mapping will be removed from the 'Invoice
                Override Expense GL Account' column of the entry</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>Sales Invoice</title>

          <para>The Sales Invoice sub menu is used to specify the default
          account to be used for the individual line items that appear on a
          Sales Invoice. The items are identified by a line description which
          can be mapped to a specific general ledger account. Sales invoices
          can be made up of a variety of items as well as the product that is
          being sold (eg discounts, promotions, work effort or labour costs
          etc). The majority of businesses will want to track these type of
          items separately in the general ledger and this screen will allow
          this type of setup.</para>

          <para>This setup will translate to one side of the journal entry
          only.</para>

          <para>A key mapping used is linked directly to the Product Type (eg
          Invoice Digital Good Item, Invoice Finished Good Item, Invoice
          Finished/Digital Good Item....). This controls where the sales
          revenue received from the sale of the product is stored in the
          general ledger</para>

          <para>Only a limited number of general ledger accounts that are
          available to be mapped. Currently this is 7 and limited to the
          accounts that have been assigned to the organisation from the Global
          Chart of Accounts that have a 'GL Account Class Id' = 'Revenue'
          (NOTE: You will see that Discounts on Sales is not available to be
          selected because it's GL Account Class Id = 'Cost of Goods Sold
          Expense'. It appears as a default because it is setup in the Global
          GL settings that doesnt seem to have any limitations of the
          account.) <important>
              <para>This screen is one of the screens where the default
              entries that are displayed here are entered via the Global GL
              Settings under the sub menu 'Invoice Item Type'. This screen
              allows users to override the global settings for the Sales
              Invoice item type. An example of why this could be necessary
              could be that a company many want to isolate the sales reporting
              of a specific department or business unit separately (eg
              subledgers etc) but still have the option of a 'catch all'
              global general ledger account.</para>
            </important></para>

          <para>If an override account is added it will appear in the Override
          GL Account column on the screen.</para>

          <para>The only mapping that seems a bit out of place here is Sales
          Tax. It is blank because Sales Tax is setup using Tax Authorities so
          dont know why you would want to override the Sales Tax account to a
          Sales Revenue Account. <note>
              <para>Also need to highlight that in the Global Settings it uses
              the ENUM description to select the item and there are duplicate
              descriptions between the Sales Invoice and the Purchase Invoice.
              Not too much of a problem here but it does cause problems in
              Agreements when setting up things like Commissions based on line
              items as you cant tell the difference between the description of
              a Sales Invoice item called 'Invoice Adjustment' and a Purchase
              Invoice item called 'Invoice Adjustment' ..... except by trial
              and error</para>
            </note></para>

          <para>How the Sales Invoice mappings are used is best shown by an
          example. A very simple description of an online Sales Order Process
          could be as follows:</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Customer Orders a Product (and Creates a Sales
              Order)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Customer Pays for Product (via Credit Card, Internet
              Banking etc)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Vendor confirms Payment and Dispatches the Product to the
              Customer</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>

          <para>Let's focus on the second part step of 3 in more
          detail.</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>The vendor has verified that the customer payment has been
              received</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>In OFBiz Order Manager they will then look up the relevant
              Sales Order and then click the 'Quick Ship Entire Order' button
              to log the dispatch of the order in the system</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Quick Ship Entire Order' button is a trigger for an
              'automatic' accounting transaction</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The transaction type that is triggered is called 'Sales
              Invoice'</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>Transaction Type: Sales Invoice DR 120000 Accounts Receivable,
          DR 410000 Discounts on Sales, DR 400000 Sales, CR 22????? Sales Tax
          Collected</para>

          <para>DR Sales is used for item promotions where product cost is
          simply reversed. Only order promotions are coded to Discounts. The
          Sales Tax account will be dependent on your sales tax setup. The
          demo data posts to tax accounts by US state.</para>

          <para>One of the CR (or Credit) entries for the Sales Invoice
          transaction is created using the Sales mapping defined here in the
          Sales Invoice (and the other is created another GL Account default
          for 'Tax Authority GL Accounts')</para>

          <para>All of the the DR (or Debit) entries for the Sales Invoice
          transaction (except for Accounts Receivable which is comes from the
          GL Account Type defaults) are created using the mappings defined
          here in the Sales Invoice</para>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I add a Sales Invoice override mapping?</title>

            <para>By default there are no Sales Invoice override mappings that
            are configured as part of the OFBiz demo data.</para>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'Invoice Item Type' from the drop down
                list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the ' Override Revenue GL Account Id' to map it
                to from the drop down list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Save' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The new mapping will be displayed in the 'Override GL
                Account' column in the list at the bottom of the screen</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I update a Sales Invoice override mapping?</title>

            <para>An existing Sales Invoice override mapping cannot be updated
            but needs to be removed and a new mapping added. If you try to add
            an override to an item that already has an override you will get a
            duplicate record error message.</para>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I remove a Sales Invoice override mapping?</title>

            <note>
              <para>Only the override mapping can be deleted. The default
              mapping record cannot be deleted here (even though the Remove
              button is displayed next to it!)</para>
            </note>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Locate the entry that needs the override deleted in the
                list of Sales Invoice override mappings</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the entry</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The override mapping will be removed from the 'Override
                GL Account' column of the entry</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>Financial Account GL Account</title>

          <para>The FinAccount Type GL Account (Financial Account Type / GL
          Account Type) is used to specify the default account to be used for
          a specific type of Financial Account. This setup will translate to
          one side of the journal entry only.</para>

          <important>
            <para>There is a limitation that only one account can be specified
            per Financial Account type. Currently there are 6 types of
            Financial Account (Bank, Deposit, Investment, Gift Certificate,
            Replenish, Service Credit) - so if you have more than one of these
            type of accounts that you need to track separately then there
            could be a problem.</para>
          </important>

          <para>This mapping is normally be triggered if something is paid or
          uses a Financial Account. Using the demo data this mapping is
          triggered when someone purchases a gift certificate, or pays money
          into a financial account.</para>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I add a new Financial Account Type / GL Account
            mapping?</title>

            <para>By default there are 4 Financial Account Type / GL Type
            mappings that are configured as part of the OFBiz demo
            data.</para>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'FinAccount Type Id' from the drop down
                list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the ' GL Account' to map it to from the drop down
                list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Add' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The new mapping will be displayed in the list at the
                bottom of the screen</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I update a Financial Account Type / GL Account
            mapping?</title>

            <para>A Financial Account Type / GL Account Type mapping can be
            updated by modifying the GL Account only. Unlike other screens in
            this area if the GL Account Type needs to be updated then it can
            be done by creating a new record with the correct GL Account type
            which will overwrite the existing record.</para>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Locate the entry that needs to be updated in the list of
                Financial Account Type / GL Account Type mappings</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Modify the 'GL Account 'by using the drop down list next
                to the GL Account field</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Update' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The updated mapping will be displayed</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I remove a Financial Account Type / GL Account
            mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Locate the entry that needs to be deleted in the list of
                Financial Account Type / GL Account Type mappings</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the entry</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>Product Category / GL Account</title>

          <para>The Product Category GL Account is used to specify the default
          account to be used for a specific 'Product Category' and 'Account
          Type' combination. This setup will translate to one side of the
          journal entry only.</para>

          <para>It is used for tracking product category transactions at a
          more detailed level. Examples could be as follows:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Tracking Accounts Receivable by Product Category in the
              General Ledger</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Tracking Cost of Goods by Product Category in the General
              Ledger</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Tracking Commissions paid by Product Category in the
              General Ledger</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <para>The demo data gives an idea of the use of product categories
          to classify or separate different products streams. If specific
          accounting or management reporting is required at this level then
          the General Ledger can be setup to provide this detail.</para>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I add a new Product Category / GL Account Type
            mapping?</title>

            <para>By default there are no Product Category / GL Account Type
            mappings that are configured as part of the OFBiz demo
            data.</para>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'Account Type' from the drop down list (NOTE:
                In other screens this field is call the 'GL Account Type
                Id'.....)</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the ' GL Account' to map it to from the drop down
                list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Enter or look up the 'Product Category Id' to be
                used</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Add' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The new mapping will be displayed in the list at the
                bottom of the screen</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I update a Product Category / GL Account type
            mapping?</title>

            <para>A Product Category / GL Account Type mapping can be updated
            by modifying the GL Account only. If the product category or the
            Account Type needs to be updated then the mapping will need to be
            deleted and then re-entered using the new product category or
            Account Type.</para>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Locate the entry that needs to be updated in the list of
                Product Category / GL Account Type mappings</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Modify the 'GL Account 'by using the drop down list next
                to the 'GL Account' field</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Update' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The updated mapping will be displayed</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I remove a Product Category / GL Account Type
            mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Locate the entry that needs to be deleted in the list of
                Product Category / GL Account Type mappings</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the entry</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>Product GL Accounts</title>

          <para>The Product GL Account is used to specify the default account
          to be used for a specific Product' and 'Account Type' combination.
          This setup will translate to one side of the journal entry
          only.</para>

          <note>
            <para>Duplicate functionality .... This setup for the Product GL
            Account can also be setup using the 'Accounts' sub menu for the
            Product in Catalog Manager. Need to confirm whether this default
            work like a hierarchy....eg Product GL Defaults will override
            General Account defaults.</para>
          </note>

          <para>It is used for tracking product transactions at a more
          detailed level. Examples could be as follows:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Tracking Accounts Receivable by Product in the General
              Ledger</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Tracking Cost of Goods by product (or product variation)
              in the General Ledger</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Tracking Commissions paid by Product in the General
              Ledger</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I add a new Product / GL Account Type
            mapping?</title>

            <para>By default there are no Product / GL Account Type mappings
            that are configured as part of the OFBiz demo data.</para>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select the 'Account Type' from the drop down list<note>
                    <para>In other screens this field is call the 'GL Account
                    Type Id'....</para>
                  </note></para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select the ' GL Account' to map it to from the drop down
                list</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Enter or look up the 'Product Id' to be used</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Add' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The new mapping will be displayed in the list at the
                bottom of the screen</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>

            <note>
              <para>This mapping can also be also be done via the 'Accounts'
              sub menu for the Product. Any mapping created here will be
              displayed under the Product 'Accounts' sub menu. Alternatively
              any mapping created in the Product 'Accounts' sub menu will also
              be displayed here.</para>
            </note>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I update a Product / GL Account Type
            mapping?</title>

            <para>A Product / GL Account Type mapping can be updated by
            modifying the GL Account only. If the product needs to be updated
            then the mapping will need to be deleted and then re-entered using
            the new product.</para>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Locate the entry that needs to be updated in the list of
                Product / GL Account Type mappings</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Modify the 'GL Account 'by using the drop down list next
                to the 'GL Account' field</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Update' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The updated mapping will be displayed</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
          </sect4>

          <sect4>
            <title>How do I delete a Product / GL Account Type
            mapping?</title>

            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Locate the entry that needs to be deleted in the list of
                Product / GL Account Type mappings</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Locate the entry that needs to be deleted in the list of
                Product / GL Account Type mappings</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>

            <note>
              <para>Locate the entry that needs to be deleted in the list of
              Product / GL Account Type mappings</para>
            </note>
          </sect4>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Time Period</title>

        <para>Time periods are a defined period of time (usually a month,
        quarter or year) that is used to group business transactions. It is a
        key part of any general accounting setup.</para>

        <para>Time periods can be used for the definition of :</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Company Financial Year</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Fiscal / Tax Periods (weeks, months, quarters)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>VAT / GST Periods</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Sales Periods</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I add a new Financial Year time period?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Using the area at the bottom of the screen labelled
              'New'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Leave the Parent Period Id field blank<note>
                  <para>The financial year will be the parent of other time
                  periods eg fiscal months or GST / VAT periods</para>
                </note></para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select 'Fiscal Year' from the 'Period Type Id' drop down
              box</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter '13' in the Period Num field <note>
                  <para>You can use any number that does not conflict with the
                  other time periods you want to use. We plan to define 12
                  fiscal or tax months so will use 13 for the year</para>
                </note></para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter 'FY 2010-2011' in the Period Name field<note>
                  <para>You can use any name you want but make sure it makes
                  sense. This example is an abbreviation for Fiscal Year
                  2010-2011</para>
                </note></para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select '1st April 2010' using the calendar lookup in the
              'From Date' field</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select '1st April 2011' using the calendar lookup in the
              'Thru Date' field<note>
                  <para>Even though we want our financial year to end on 31st
                  March 2011 the test used is based on less than not an equal
                  to</para>
                </note></para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Leave the 'Is Closed' field at its default of 'No'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Create' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The new time period will now be displayed in the list of
              open time periods.</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I add a new GST/ VAT time period?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Using the area at the bottom of the screen labelled
              'New'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select the previously created financial year 'FY
              2010-2011' in the Parent Period Id field</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select 'Fiscal Month' from the 'Period Type Id' drop down
              box</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter '1' in the Period Num field <note>
                  <para>This is the first of 12 periods that we want to
                  define.</para>
                </note></para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter 'FM April 2010' in the Period Name field <note>
                  <para>You can use any name you want but make sure it makes
                  sense. This example is an abbreviation for Fiscal Month
                  April 2010</para>
                </note></para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select '1st April 2010' using the calendar lookup in the
              'From Date' field</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select '1st May 2010' using the calendar lookup in the
              'Thru Date' field<note>
                  <para>Even though we want our fiscal month to end on 30th
                  April 2010 the test is used is based on less than not an
                  equal to</para>
                </note></para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Leave the Is Closed field at its default of 'No'</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Create' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The new time period will now be displayed in the list of
              open time periods.</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I update a time period?</title>

          <para>Time periods cannot be updated via the current time periods
          screen. If you need to amend time period details then it can be done
          via Entity Data Maintenance in the Webtools menu.</para>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I close a time period?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>To close a time period select the 'Close' button next to
              the time period.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The time period will be removed from the current open time
              periods area and re-displayed in the closed time periods section
              of the screen.</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>

          <note>
            <para>Closing a time period is a trigger for an automatic
            accounting transaction as follows:</para>

            <itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Transaction Type: Period Closing</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>DR ?????? (based on the GL account type mapping for
                Profit Loss)</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>CR 336000 Retained Earnings (based on GL account type
                mapping for Retained Earnings)</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
          </note>

          <note>
            <para>Both sides of this accounting transaction uses the same GL
            account type default mapping. The account mapping for 'Profit
            Loss' is not setup as part of the demo data so this transaction
            will not automatically post to the general ledger but will instead
            be put in the ERROR_JOURNAL as an unposted transaction. The
            transaction value is zero for both sides of journal...Even if it
            does have a value do we want to move it from P and L to Equity
            during the financial year? Normally this is done once at the end
            of the financial year.</para>
          </note>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Journals</title>

        <para>A journal is a detailed accounting transaction that is recorded
        (or posted) to the General Ledger. It is made up of a debit and a
        credit component.<important>
            <para>A journal is a detailed accounting transaction that is
            recorded (or posted) to the General Ledger. It is made up of a
            debit and a credit component</para>
          </important></para>

        <note>
          <para>By default in OFBIZ a journal called 'ERROR_JOURNAL' is
          created as part of the demo data installation.This 'ERROR_JOURNAL'
          is referenced in the Accounting Preferences setup for 'Company'. The
          'ERROR_JOURNAL' is used to store details of any transaction that
          fails and cannot be posted to a general ledger account. Transactions
          falling into error can be as the result of incomplete setup or an
          invalid transaction (eg a transaction that should never
          occur).</para>
        </note>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I create a journal?</title>

          <para><orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>Enter a journal name in the Gl Journal Name field (eg
                MY_JOURNAL)</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
              </listitem>

              <listitem>
                <para>The journal is created and will appear in the journal
                list at the bottom of the screen</para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist></para>

          <note>
            <para>The Journal ID is automatically generated</para>
          </note>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I update a journal?</title>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select the journal to be updated from the list of journals
              at the bottom of the screen</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The journal details will be displayed on the screen</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Update the Gl Journal Name (as this is currently the only
              field that can be updated)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Submit' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The updated journal will appear in the journal list at the
              bottom of the screen</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I delete a journal?</title>

          <para>Be careful if you need to remove an existing journal as it may
          have transactions associated with it.</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Remove' button next to the journal that you
              want to delete</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The journal is deleted and the screen is
              redisplayed</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>

      <sect2>
        <title>Chart of Accounts</title>

        <para>OFBiz comes with a master template for a very comprehensive
        chart of accounts. This can be found in 'Global GL Defaults' under the
        'Accounting' tab.</para>

        <para>A couple of points to note</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>you do not need to use all the accounts defined in this
            master template (but it may be simpler to look for the accounts
            that you can use or rename)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>you can create your own additional accounts if you dont want
            to use the ones in the master template</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>The chart of accounts for the default organisation (Company) is
        built up by selecting the accounts that you want to use from the
        global chart of accounts master template. This means that if you want
        to create a new account then you need to create it first in the Global
        Chart of Accounts and then link (or assign) it to the chart of
        accounts for Company.</para>

        <para>Details of the Chart of Accounts can be exported as a CSV file
        or PDF using the buttons displayed.</para>

        <important>
          <para>You need to be careful if you do decide to create your own
          accounts that they contain all the details required and that they
          are linked into the relevant configuation for the setup of the GL
          defaults. This means that if you change an account (eg Inventory) to
          one of your own - you need to check the GL defaults setup and
          replace any reference to the Inventory account to the one you have
          created.</para>
        </important>

        <para>This Chart of Accounts screen is used to define the list of
        accounts (or chart) that will be actively used by the company.For
        example the Global chart of accounts may contain 100 different
        accounts but only 20 need to be used for your specific business. This
        means the you need only to create assignments to the accounts that you
        actively want to use.</para>

        <para>The Chart of Accounts is a mixture of business needs (ie being
        able to track the information you need for your business) and tax
        requirements (i.e. legal or government requirements necessary for
        operating a business). The type of Chart that you setup will be
        dependent of your business type.</para>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I create a Chart of Accounts?</title>

          <para>As mentioned above the chart of accounts for the default
          organisation (Company) is built up by selecting the accounts that
          you want to use from the global chart of accounts master template.
          This means that if you want to create a new account then you need to
          create it first in the Global Chart of Accounts and then link (or
          assign) it to the chart of accounts for Company. By creating an
          assignment to an account it is then added to the Chart of
          Accounts.</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select the account Gl Account Id that you need from the
              drop down box</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Create Assignment' button</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The account is added to the Chart of Account</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I create a Chart of Accounts?</title>

          <para>Updating the Chart of Accounts will involve either creating a
          new assignment or removing an existing one. A new assignment is
          created using the instructions above. The added complication may be
          that the account that you need does not exist in the Global Chart of
          Accounts. As mentioned above it will need to be created and then
          linked.</para>

          <para>See the instructions below to remove an existing account
          assignment.</para>

          <note>
            <para>If a completely new account is required that does not
            already exist as part of the Global Chart of Accounts template
            then it will need to be created as part of the Global template
            first before it can be used as an assignment in the Organisation
            Chart of Accounts.</para>
          </note>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I delete a Chart of Accounts?</title>

          <para>Accounts are not deleted from the Chart of Accounts - they are
          simply no longer selected to be used.</para>

          <para>It is important that you do not remove accounts that are
          active and have already been used for transactions. Even if the net
          balance of the account is zero then from an audit perspective then
          you should not be removing accounts.</para>

          <para>You should only be looking to remove accounts that have not
          been used. To un-link or un-assign accounts from the default company
          then use the Entity Data Maintenance from the Webtools menu. Look
          for the entity 'GlAccountOrganization' and delete the record to
          remove the link.</para>
        </sect3>

        <sect3>
          <title>How do I update the details for an account in the Chart of
          Accounts?</title>

          <para>Details of the accounts that make up the Chart of Accounts can
          be accessed from this screen.</para>

          <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Click on the 'GL Account Id' of the account
              required</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>The 'Edit GL Account' screen is displayed showing the
              details of the account selected (NOTE:This screen is also
              accessible via 'Global GL Settings / Chart of Account / Navigate
              Accounts '</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Amend the fields required (NOTE: The GL Account Id and
              Posted Balance fields cannot be amended)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Press the 'Update' button</para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </sect3>
      </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
      <title>Accounting</title>

      <para>Click Accounting in the Available Internal Organizations list to
      open to go to the Accounting menu. The Accounting menu includes options
      for:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Accounts Summary</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Account Reconciliation</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Account Reconciliations</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Accounting Transactions</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Accounting Transactions Entries</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Reports</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Checks</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>

  <preface>
    <title/>

    <para/>
  </preface>
</book>
